原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译          迈阿密·人妻  杏仁斯嘉丽  arcadiachi  杀手女王辰星晓
校对          杀手女王辰星晓
时间轴      映映  荞麦麦  紫夏
时间轴      纸袋  没有影子  壬虚浪影
后期          拉图
总监          杀手女王辰星晓
波西米亚狂想曲
现在是伦敦时间正午12点
It's 12:00 noon in London.
费城时间早上7点
7 a.m. in Philadelphia.
全世界瞩目的"拯救生命"演唱会现在开启
And around the world, it's time for Live Aid.
温布利球场迎来了尊贵的
Wembley welcomes their Royal Highnesses...
Somebody to Love
♪ Each morning I get up I die a little ♪
威尔士亲王与王妃
the Prince and Princess of Wales.
♪ Can barely stand on my feet ♪
♪ Take a look in the mirror and cry ♪
♪ Lord what you're doing to me ♪
♪ I have spent all my years in believing you ♪
♪ But I just can't get no relief, Lord ♪
♪ Somebody ♪
♪ Ooh, somebody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
♪ Somebody to love ♪
♪ I work hard (he works hard) every day of my life ♪
♪ I work 'til I ache my bones ♪
♪ At the end (at the end of the day) ♪
♪ I take home my hard-earned pay all on my own ♪
♪ I get down (down) on my knees (knees) ♪
♪ And I start to pray (praise the Lord) ♪
♪ 'Til the tears run down from my eyes, Lord ♪
♪ Somebody ♪
♪ Ooh, somebody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
♪ Somebody to love ♪
大卫  看这里
David, look at me.
♪ Everyday I try and I try and I try ♪
♪ But everybody wants to put me down ♪
♪ They say I'm goin' crazy ♪
♪ They say I got a lot of water in my brain ♪
♪ No, I got no common sense ♪
♪ I got nobody left to believe ♪
♪ I just gotta get out of this prison cell ♪
♪ Someday I'm gonna be free, Lord ♪
♪ Find me somebody to love ♪
♪ Somebody ♪
♪ Can anybody find me ♪
♪ Somebody to love ♪
伦敦      年
喂  你掉了一件行李  巴基仔
Oi! You missed one, Pakkie!
我不是从巴基斯坦来的
I'm not from Pakistan.
Doing All Right
♪ Yesterday my life was in ruin ♪
♪ Now today I know what I'm doing ♪
你是我的
我拥有你
永远爱你
♪ Gotta feeling, I should be doing alright ♪
神父  我有罪
在怒火中冲你大喊
骗子  你欺骗了我
请原谅我
晚饭好了
Dinner is ready.
我不饿  妈
I'm not hungry, Mum.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
-跟朋友一起出去  -女孩子吗
- Out with friends. - A girl?
-妈  -看看你
- Oh, Mum. - Look at you.
快给妈妈一个吻
Give your mother a kiss.
我要迟到了
I'm going to be late.
你总是迟到
You're always late.
爸  工作怎么样
Hi, Papa. How was work?
又出门吗  法鲁克
Out again, Farrokh?
我现在叫弗雷迪了  爸
It's Freddie now, Papa.
弗雷迪  法鲁克
Freddie or Farrokh...
光改名字有什么用  你还不是每晚出门
what difference does it make when you're out every night...
脑子里对未来没半点规划
no thought of the future in your head?
睿智  善语  良行
Good thoughts, good words, good deeds.
这些才是你应立志追求的
That's what you should aspire to.
是的
Yes.
那你追求这些的结果又如何呢
And how's that worked out for you?
♪ 一切顺利 ♪
♪ Doing alright ♪
♪ 明天此时我会身在何处 ♪
♪ Where will I be this time tomorrow ♪
♪ 沉浸在喜悦中亦或是悲伤中 ♪
♪ Jumped in joy or sinking in sorrow ♪
♪ 总而言之  我会一切顺利 ♪
♪ Anyway, I should be doing alright ♪
他们比上周的好
Yeah, they're better than last week.
-这个乐队很酷  -确实不错
- They're a cool band. - Yeah, not bad.
♪ 一切顺利 ♪
♪ Doing alright ♪
喝点什么
What can I get for you?
大杯拉格
Pint of lager.
-谢谢你  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
别忘记微笑
♪ 本应等太阳升起 ♪
♪ Should be waiting for the sun ♪
♪ 可我却需要躲藏 ♪
♪ Anyway I've got to hide away ♪
回见  伙计
See you, mate.
烟枪屋乐队
Humpy Bong?
Humpy Bong.
他们有很多巡演  他们会火的
They're going places. They're gonna be big.
烟枪屋乐队  你在开玩笑吗
Humpy Bong? Are you joking?
别这样  蒂姆
Don't do it, Tim.
我很抱歉  伙计们  但...
No, I'm sorry, guys, but...
我们这样下去没有出路
we're not going anywhere with this.
就这些吗  在大学  酒吧演出
What? College gigs, pubs?
总得放手一搏
Gotta give it a go.
所以我就跟他说"不  你不能这样做"
So I just said to him, "No, you can't do that."
你真的什么都听不到
You literally can't hear anything.
有点儿傻
It's a bit silly.
然后所有人就都穿起了长裙
But then everyone else was in, like, long dresses?
多奇怪啊
How bizarre.
你还好吗
You all right?
抱歉  我在找乐队
Sorry. Oh, I was just looking for the band.
他们通常都在后面
They're usually out back.
我喜欢你的外套
I like your coat.
别忘记微笑
是碧芭的
It's from Biba.
她在那儿工作
She works there.
多谢你啊
Thank you.
我觉得他说的没错
I think he's right.
刚那演出确实是一堆屎
That show was a load of bollocks.
确实有可以改进的地方
Well, there was room for improvement, yeah.
周六晚上我本有更好的事可干
I've got better things to do with my Saturday nights.
我可以告诉你她们的名字
I could give you their names.
演出很不错
I enjoyed the show.
-谢谢  伙计  -谢谢你
- Thanks, man. - Thank you.
其实我看你们的演出看了一阵子了
I've been following you for a while, actually.
微笑乐队
Smile.
牙科学生起这个名字确实合适
Makes sense for a dental student.
你是学天体物理学的  对吗
And you're astrophysics, aren't you?
-是的  -所以你是聪明的那个
- Yeah. - Makes you the clever one.
是啊  我想是的
Yeah, I suppose it does, yeah.
我在这儿学设计
I study design here.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
而且  我还写歌
Also, um, I write songs.
也许你们会感兴趣
Might be of interest to you.
其实只是个爱好
It's just a bit of fun, really.
你晚来了五分钟
Well, you're five minutes too late.
我们的主唱刚不干了
Our lead singer just quit.
那你们需要一个新人
Well, then you'll need someone new.
有推荐吗
Any ideas?
我怎么样
What about me?
你这牙可不行  伙计
Not with those teeth, mate.
♪ 我知道自己在做什么 ♪
♪ I know what I'm doin' ♪
♪ 我有种感觉 ♪
♪ I got a feeling ♪
♪ 我会一切顺利 ♪
♪ I should be doing all right... ♪
♪ 一切顺利 ♪
♪ Doing all right... ♪
我天生多长四颗门牙
I was born with four additional incisors.
口腔空间大就意味着更高的音域
More space in my mouth means more range.
我会考虑你们的邀请的
I'll consider your offer.
你会弹贝斯吗
Uh, do you play bass?
不会
Nope.
碧芭
抱歉  谢谢
Excuse me. Thanks.
你找到我了
So, you found me, then.
需要帮忙吗
How can I help you?
我挺喜欢这条的
Um, I rather liked these.
有我的尺码吗
Do you think you have them in my size?
这是女装区  所以我不太确定
This is the ladies' section, so I'm not exactly sure.
这里也没个标志之类的
There wasn't a sign or anything.
我觉得这其实不重要  不是吗
I don't think it should really matter, do you?
我觉得你可能会喜欢这个
I thought you might like this.
你真的可以进来的吗
Are you even allowed to be in here?
其实不可以
No, not really.
还有一步
One more thing.
可以吗
May I?
你长得很有异域风情
You have such an exotic look.
我喜欢你的风格
I love your style.
我觉得我们都应该多去冒险
I think we should all take more risks.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
谢谢  谢谢你
Oh, cheers. Thank you.
大家好
Hello, everybody.
我们乐队加入了几张新面孔
We've got a few fresh faces.
这是约翰·迪肯  贝斯手
This is John Deacon, our bass player.
还有我们的新主唱
Yeah, and our new lead singer...
弗雷迪  博...博萨拉
Freddie Bul... Bulsara...
弗雷迪·博萨拉
Freddie Bulsara.
就是我
That's right.
当然还有罗杰  最重要的成员
And Roger, of course. The biggest member of them all.
罗杰
Hey, Roger!
你们好啊  美丽的人儿
Hello, all you beautiful people.
蒂姆去哪了
Where's Tim?
这个巴基仔是谁啊
Who's the Pakkie?
准备好了吗  费雷迪
Ready, Freddie?
我们开始吧
Let's do it.
♪ 活出精彩 ♪
♪ Keep yourself alive ♪
♪ 人生路上的艰辛 ♪
♪ I was told a million times ♪
♪ 已被说过无数次 ♪
♪ Of all the troubles in my way ♪
♪ 记得要多涨智慧 ♪
♪ Mind you grow a little wiser ♪
♪ 每天都要变更好 ♪
♪ Little better every day ♪
♪ 但若我跨过无数条河流 ♪
♪ But if I rode a million rivers ♪
♪ 走过数百万里路 ♪
♪ And I crossed a million miles ♪
不对
No, no.
♪ 却仍在原地 ♪
♪ Still be where I started ♪
歌词错了
Wrong lyric!
♪ 为生计强颜欢笑 ♪
♪ Bread and butter for a smile ♪
歌词错了
Wrong lyric!
♪ 在购物街 ♪
♪ Sold a million mirrors ♪
♪ 卖出百万面镜子 ♪
♪ In shopping alley ways ♪
♪ 却从未见我容颜 ♪
♪ But I never saw my face ♪
♪ 出现在任何橱窗 ♪
♪ In any window any day ♪
♪ 现在家人朋友都这么说 ♪
♪ Now they say your folks are telling you ♪
♪ 做个超级明星 ♪
♪ Be a super star ♪
♪ 但我要告诉你  要满足 ♪
♪ But I tell you, just be satisfied ♪
♪ 就保持你现在的样子 ♪
♪ And stay right where you are ♪
♪ 活出精彩 ♪
♪ Keep yourself alive ♪
♪ 所有人  活出精彩 ♪
♪ All you people, keep yourself alive ♪
记记歌词  弗雷迪
Learn the song, Freddie.
一年后
Keep Yourself Alive
♪ Do you think you're better every day? ♪
♪ No, I just think I'm two steps nearer to my grave ♪
宽敞的录音棚
♪ Keep yourself alive (come on) ♪
♪ All you people keep yourself alive ♪
你们迟到了
You're late.
这太扯了
This is bollocks!
应该是逆时针  我觉得你能做到  约翰
It's counterclockwise, I think you'll find, John.
是吗  谢谢你  布莱恩
Oh, is it? Thank you, Brian.
你想来试试吗  别客气
Would you like to do it? Please, feel free.
不不  你做得很好
No, no, no. Doing a good job.
格拉斯哥南边每个酒吧和大学的演出都卖空了
We sold out every pub and uni south of Glasgow...
可我却困在这鸟不拉屎的地方
and I'm stuck in the middle of nowhere,
吃一个火腿三明治
eating a ham sandwich!
问题是  我们的目标还不够远大
Trouble is, we're just not thinking big enough.
你有什么想法  弗雷
What have you got in mind, Fred?
专辑
An album.
我们录不起专辑
We can't afford an album.
我们会找到办法的
Oh, we'll find a way.
你们觉得这辆车能卖多少钱
How much do you think we can get for this van?
我希望你是在开玩笑
I hope you're joking.
这可相当于三个月的薪水
That's three months' wages.
还有一辆超好的车
And a perfectly good van.
别太大惊小怪了  亲爱的
Don't be so dramatic, darling.
你今晚可是要录专辑了  我们走
You're recording an album tonight. Let's go!
微笑乐队  第四节
你们不觉得我听起来很糟糕吗
Don't you think I sound like shit?
不  还不错
No, it's good.
-我们能再来一次吗  -当然
- Can we try it again? - Sure, yeah.
当然  反正烧的是你们的钱
Sure, it's your money.
还真是
Literally.
♪ 你是我的  我拥有你 ♪
♪ You are mine I possess you ♪
♪ 我永远属于你 ♪
♪ I belong to you forever ♪
听起来好多了
Sounds a lot better.
我们得多来点实验性的东西
We need to get experimental.
试试让"啊啊啊"在左右声道跳跃
Try bouncing us left and right for the ah-ah-ahs.
♪ 你是我的  我拥有你 ♪
♪ You are mine I possess you ♪
♪ 我永远属于你 ♪
♪ I belong to you forever ♪
最后一个放在正中间
Now dead center for the last.
最后再调高
And then blast it!
太棒了
Yes!
Seven Seas Of Rhye
♪ Fear me, you lords and lady preachers ♪
♪ I descend upon your earth from the skies ♪
很棒  对吗
That's good, right?
♪ I command your very souls you unbelievers ♪
我们还有时间再采一些样吗
Do we have time to stack a few more?
♪ Bring before me what is mine ♪
录音棚八点开门  所以我们还有三十分钟
The studio opens at 8:00, so we got 30 more minutes.
♪ The seven seas of Rhye ♪
♪ Sister, I live and lie for you ♪
♪ You are mine I possess you ♪
-这听起来不错  对吗  -是啊
- That sounds good, right? - Yeah.
♪ I belong to you forever ♪
RT  在录音间的这些小子们是谁
Oi, RT, who are these kids in the box?
一支学生乐队搞些奇奇怪怪的东西
A student band doing some weird stuff.
样带呢  你有吗
How about demos? You got some?
熬了一晚上呢  伙计
Been up all night, mate.
皇后
新名字是皇后乐队吗
So the new name is Queen?
就是"女王陛下"
As in "Her Royal Highness."
而且这名字让人很震惊
And because it's outrageous...
我想不出比我更令人震惊的了
and I can't think of anyone more outrageous than me.
这是最不实用的床了
This is the most impractical bed.
很好听
That's beautiful.
这曲调能写成歌
Think it has potential.
-我得去上班  -我不同意
- I have to go to work. - I simply won't allow it.
如果我被辞退  你要养我吗
You're going to support me if I get fired?
我会一直照顾你的
I'll always look after you.
我要...
I'm going to...
我要迟到了
I'm going to be late.
你真美
How beautiful you are.
我小的时候
When I was a little girl...
总是在房子里乱跑藏起来
I used to run around the house and hide and...
他找不到我
he couldn't find me.
聪明的姑娘
Clever girl.
请告诉你父亲我很高兴能见到他
Please tell your father it's nice to meet him.
我说了
I have.
那谢谢他带来可爱的生日蛋糕
Then thank him for the lovely birthday cake.
我说了
I have.
那跟他说他女儿床上功夫了得
Then tell him his daughter's an epic shag.
弗雷迪  他会读唇语
Freddie, he can read lips.
玛丽
Mary...
我等了很久才等到法鲁克
I can't tell you how long I have waited for Farrokh...
带回家一个像你一样的好姑娘
to bring home a nice girl like you.
法鲁克
Farrokh?
法鲁克没跟你说他是在桑给巴尔出生的吗
Did Farrokh not tell you he was born in Zanzibar?
他没说过
No, he did not.
-我以前认识一个桑给巴尔的姑娘  -等等
- I used to know a girl who was Zanzibari. - One minute.
我以为弗雷迪是在伦敦出生的
I thought Freddie was born in London.
-他是的  十八岁"生"的  -闭嘴
- Oh, he was. At the age of 18. - Shut up.
我们家是印度帕西人
Our family is Indian Parsee.
-妈  妈  妈  -玛丽
- Mum. Mum, Mum. - Mary...
-妈  -妈  拜托
- Mum. - Mum, please...
来  看看这个
Here. Have a look at these.
-太好了  -拜托  拜托
- Yes. Yeah. - Please! Please.
-快停下  -我们得看看
- No stopping. - We need to see those.
一千年前
A thousand years ago,
帕西人从波斯逃到印度
the Parsees fled to India from Persia...
躲避穆斯林的迫害
to escape Muslim persecution.
真的吗  那太糟了
Really? That's terrible.
那你们为什么离开桑给巴尔
So why did you leave Zanzibar?
我们不是离开
We didn't leave.
他好小
He's so small.
我们什么都没有带  就被赶走了
We were chased out with just the clothes on our backs.
其实他是个不错的拳手
He was quite a good boxer, actually.
♪ 祝我生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to me ♪
他必须是
He had to be.
他的对手总是冲着他的牙去
His opponents went for his teeth
♪ 祝我生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to me ♪
总是想把他的牙打进去
always trying to punch them in.
绝对是个目标
Certainly a target.
♪ 祝默丘里生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to Mercury ♪
这张照片里他多大
So how old is he in this photo?
我想差不多三四岁
I think three or four years old.
是吗  那个年纪就打拳击了
Really? Boxing already at that age?
真好
So good.
♪ 祝我生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy Birthday to me ♪
默丘里
Mercury?
再也不回头
No looking back.
只前进
Only forward.
现在连家族姓氏都配不上你了吗
So now the family name's not good enough for you?
只是个艺名
It's just a stage name.
不  不是
No, it's not.
我已经正式更名了
I changed it legally.
换了新的护照之类的
Got a new passport and everything.
卡什  这时你多大
Kash, how old are you here?
我不知道
I don't know.
这是在弗雷迪去寄宿学校之前
It was before Freddie went off to boarding school.
我把法鲁克送走
I sent Farrokh away
是想让他成为一名优秀的帕西男孩
to make a good Parsee boy of him.
他太疯太任性
He was too wild and unruly.
但又有什么用
But what good did it do?
睿智  善语  良行
Good thoughts, good words, good deeds.
Lazing on a Sunday Afternoon
♪ 我来自伦敦城 ♪
♪ I come from London town ♪
假装自己是别人
You can't get anywhere
♪ 只是个普通人 ♪
♪ I'm just an ordinary guy ♪
不会有任何前途
pretending to be someone you're not.
谁想吃点蛋糕
Who'd like some cake?
♪ 周五我会去卢浮宫画画 ♪
♪ Fridays I go painting in the Louvre ♪
蛋糕总是很好吃
Cake is always good.
您好
Hello?
稍等
Just a moment.
弗雷迪·默丘里
Freddie Mercury.
有你的电话
Phone call.
这名字真好听
Quite like the sound of that.
弗雷迪说你是什么科学家
Freddie tells me that you're some sort of a scientist.
-其实是天体物理学  -好吧
- Astrophysics, actually. - Oh.
如果我能读下去我父亲会很高兴
Yeah, my father would've preferred it if I continued.
-什么时候  -你得很聪明吧
- When? - That's very clever.
-他是个牙医  -我从来不是牙医
- He's a dentist. - I was never a dentist.
-我想看看这张照片  -他就是个牙医
- That's a picture I want to see. - He's a dentist.
我知道了
I see.
-那其实也得很聪明  -卡什
- That's also quite clever, actually. - Kash...
你等会做什么
what are you doing later?
做作业
Homework.
不过是聊聊而已
Just making conversation.
那时候他都听些什么音乐
What kind of music was he listening to back in those days?
他会听小理查德
Uh, he was listening to Little Richard.
-真不错  -理查德  是啊
- Very good. - Richard, yeah.
还有他的第一支乐队
And his first band...
我有事情要宣布
I have an announcement.
一位负责艺人开发的先生
One of the A&R men...
EMI公司的  看到我们录音
from EMI saw us recording.
把我们的样带给了约翰·里德
Gave our demo to John Reid.
他可是管理艾尔顿·约翰的
He looks after Elton John.
天呐
Oh, my God.
里德先生想见我们
Mr. Reid wants to meet us...
甚至有可能做我们的经纪人
and possibly, even manage us.
-不会吧  -你在开玩笑吧
- Shut up. - You're joking!
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
你确定他说的是12点吗
You're sure he said 12 o'clock?
是的  "正午酒吧见  别喝醉了"
Yes. "Midday at the pub, don't be drunk."
他是这么说的
That's what he said.
-你看着有点紧张  布莱恩  -约翰  我没事
- You look a bit nervous, Brian. - John, I'm fine.
你总是特别明显
You're usually so particular.
放松点
You just gotta be cool.
基佬
Wanker.
我怎么不知道这是化装舞会  弗雷
I didn't know it was fancy dress, Fred.
我得给别人留下深刻印象  亲爱的
I've gotta make an impression, darling.
你看起来像只愤怒的蜥蜴
You look like an angry lizard.
-说得太好了  -绝妙
- It's your best work. - Very subtle.
你是要飞走吗
You gonna fly away?
周日去教堂礼拜我能借一下吗
Can I borrow it for Sunday church?
你们就是皇后乐队啊
So, this is Queen.
你一定是弗雷迪·默丘里
And you must be Freddie Mercury.
你很有天赋
You've got a gift.
你们都很有天赋
You all have.
跟我说说
So tell me...
跟我见过的那些想要成为摇滚明星的乐队相比
what makes Queen any different
皇后乐队有什么与众不同之处
from all the other wannabe rock stars I meet?
我来跟你说有什么不同
I'll tell you what it is.
我们四个格格不入  没什么归属感
We're four misfits who don't belong together,
我们为其他格格不入的人演奏
playing to the other misfits.
那些总是待在后面
The outcasts right at the back of the room...
心里清楚自己格格不入的异类
who are pretty sure they don't belong either.
我们是属于他们的乐队
We belong to them.
我们是家人
We're a family.
但又各不相同
But no two of us are the same.
保罗
Paul.
保罗·普兰特
Paul Prenter...
来见见皇后乐队
meet Queen...
我们新签下的乐队
our new signing.
-保罗会照顾你们的日常  -幸会
- Paul will be looking after your day-to-day. - Pleasure.
如果我能让电台播你们的音乐
If I can get you on the radio...
也许就能让你们上电视
maybe I can get you on television.
-《流行音乐最前端》  -有希望
- Top of the Pops? - Hopefully.
之后呢
And then?
还"之后"呢
And then...
那只不过是全国最火的电视节目
it's only the biggest television program in the country.
没人听说过你们
No one's ever even heard of you.
听着  我很欣赏你们的积极性
Look, I admire your enthusiasm.
如果一切顺利  如果可以的话
If it goes well, if it happens...
我还考虑让你们去日本做推广巡演
I've got a promotional tour of Japan in mind.
我们想要更多
We'll want more.
每支乐队都想要更多
Every band wants more.
不是所有乐队都是皇后乐队
Every band's not Queen.
-听着  我理解  -快
- Listen, I understand. - Hurry up.
我理解这是BBC的制度
I understand that it's the policy of the BBC.
-我们是有程序的  -这简直是屎
- We have procedures. - This is shit!
拜托请你跟乐队解释一下
I need you to explain it to the band, please.
-好  快点儿  -弗雷迪  伙计们
- Okay, let's make it quick. - Freddie, boys.
听着  伙计们  我们会用录音播放
Look, chaps, it is going to be playback.
只需要对嘴唱
Lip synch's all that's required.
我们知道怎么演奏乐器
We do know how to play our instruments.
你想让我对嘴唱
You want me to lip synch?
我不理解为什么我们不能现场演奏
I don't understand why we can't simply perform live.
反正观众看不出差别
The audience will never know the difference.
我们能知道这该死的差别
We'll know the bloody difference.
这里是BBC
This is the BBC.
在这儿就得这么做  明白吗
That's how things are done around here. All right?
别做烦人精
Don't be a nuisance.
弗雷迪  演出会很棒的
Freddie, it'll be great.
你只需要确保没人盯着你的嘴看就好
You'll just have to make sure no one's looking at your lips.
这里的一切都是胡扯  老伙计
Well, the way things are done are a load of bollocks, old chap.
这里是BBC
This is the BBC.
我倒是松了口气
I'm relieved.
可不是嘛
You would be.
完美演出
Perfect performance.
♪ 她是杀手女王 ♪
♪ She's a Killer Queen ♪
♪ 火药般火辣  明胶般滑嫩 ♪
♪ Gunpowder, gelatine ♪
♪ 爆炸时如镭射光束般闪耀 ♪
♪ Dynamite with a laser beam ♪
♪ 一定会让你意乱情迷 ♪
♪ Guaranteed to blow your mind ♪
♪ 任何时候 ♪
♪ Anytime ♪
二号机位  只拍腰部以上
Number two, only above the waist.
摄像机抬起来
Camera up!
二号机位
Camera two!
没人想在吃饭的时候看这个
No one wants to see this while they're eating their meal.
♪ 一瞬间  她就如 ♪
♪ Drop of a hat she's as willing as ♪
♪ 小猫般有趣 ♪
♪ Playful as a pussy cat ♪
♪ 突然就停下 ♪
♪ Momentarily out of action ♪
♪ 暂时没了兴致 ♪
♪ temporarily out of gas ♪
♪ 这会让你发狂  发狂 ♪
♪ To absolutely drive you wild, wild ♪
给大家唱歌是什么感觉
What was it like singing for all those people?
当我知道他们在听我唱歌
When I know they're listening...
当我知道我真的走进了他们心里
when I know I really have them...
我就算想唱跑调都不可能
I couldn't sing off-key if I tried.
我如今成为了我生来就要成为的那个人
I'm exactly the person I was always meant to be.
我什么都不怕
I'm not afraid of anything.
另外一个让我有同样感觉的时刻
The only other time I ever feel that way
就是跟你在一起的时候
is when I'm with you.
别动
Don't move.
你是我此生挚爱
You're the love of my life.
弗雷迪
Freddie.
我应该戴哪根手指呢
Which finger do I put this on?
结婚的那根
Wedding finger.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
当然
Yes!
你打算让它一直呆在盒子里吗
Are you gonna leave it in the box?
弗雷迪  这太漂亮了
Freddie, it's beautiful.
我很喜欢
I love it.
答应我你永远不会摘下来
Promise me you'll never take it off.
我答应你
Oh, I promise.
无论发生什么
No matter what.
我爱你  弗雷迪
I love you, Freddie.
你会有了不起的成就的
You're going to do such great things.
我们会有了不起的成就的
We're going to do great things.
你的电话打不通
Your phone's off the hook.
这是克丽丝朵
This is Crystal.
是谢丽尔
Cheryl!
对  没错  是我记错了
Oh, that's right. My mistake.
卫生间在哪儿
Where's your loo?
走廊尽头
Uh, just down the hall.
请进啊  请随意
Oh, come on in. Make yourselves at home.
别管我们
Don't mind us.
你好  玛丽  你爸爸怎么样
Hello, Mary. How's your dad?
很好  谢谢关心
Yeah, pretty well. Thanks.
-很好  -有事吗  布莱恩
- Good. - What's going on, Brian?
如果你接了电话  你就会知道
Well, if you'd answered your phone, you'd know already.
现在真的不太方便  伙计们
This really isn't a good time, guys.
约翰·里德今天打电话过来了
John Reid called today.
他准备为我们安排一个小巡演
He has a little tour in mind for us.
一点儿也不小  布莱恩
It's not little, Brian.
他帮我们定了美国的巡演
He's booked us a tour of America.
专辑在美国冲上了排行榜
The album's hit the charts in the U.S.!
太棒了
Oh, yes!
Yes!
太棒了
梦想成真
It's happening!
准备好开启摇滚之旅了吗
Now, who wants to take a ride?
Fat Bottomed Girls
♪ 我和我的乐队一起 ♪
♪ I've been singing with my band ♪
美国中西部
♪ 全世界去表演 ♪
♪ 'cross the water, 'cross the land ♪
♪ 一路上见到了不少碧眼美女 ♪
♪ I've seen every blue-eyed floozy on the way ♪
♪ 但她们的美貌和风格 ♪
♪ But their beauty and their style ♪
♪ 越看越顺眼 ♪
♪ Went kinda smooth after a while ♪
♪ 把我带到这些可爱的美女身边 ♪
♪ Take me to them lovely ladies every time ♪
♪ 来吧 ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ 带我回家吧 ♪
♪ Oh you gonna take me home tonight ♪
♪ 坐到红红的炉火边 ♪
♪ Oh down beside your red firelight ♪
我们爱你  克利夫兰
We love you, Cleveland!
我们爱你  休斯顿
We love you, Houston!
♪ 把你的一切都给我 ♪
♪ Oh, and you give it all you got ♪
♪ 肥臀女孩你维持了摇滚世界的运行 ♪
♪ Fat bottomed girls you make the rockin' world go round ♪
我们爱你  丹佛  很高兴来这里
We love you, Denver! Very happy to be here!
观众很多吗
And are the crowds big?
每晚演出的票都卖空了
Well, we're selling out every night.
我真希望你能在这儿看看
I just wish you were here to see it.
大家真的很爱我们
They really love us.
我们爱你  波特兰
We love you, Portland!
♪ 如今我有了房贷和家 ♪
♪ Now I got mortgages and homes ♪
他也有大屁股
He's got a big ass, too!
♪ 关节也开始僵硬 ♪
♪ I got stiffness in the bones ♪
我们爱你  新奥尔良
We love you, New Orleans!
♪ 失去了往日的风采 ♪
♪ Ain't no beauty queens in this locality ♪
我们爱你  亚特兰大
We love you, Atlanta!
♪ 但我依然快乐 ♪
♪ Oh, but I still get my pleasure ♪
♪ 依然拥有巨大的宝藏 ♪
♪ Still got my greatest treasure ♪
罗  下来跟大家打个招呼
Rog, come down here and say hello.
我们爱你  匹兹堡
We love you, Pittsburgh!
-罗杰  -开始吧
- Roger! - Now, hit it!
我很好  就是很想你
I'm good. I just miss you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
没我你怎么可能过得开心
You can't possibly be having any fun without me.
没有比美国巡演更激动人心的了
Nothing as exciting as America.
♪ 坐到红红的炉火边 ♪
♪ Oh down beside that red firelight ♪
♪ 让这一切发酵 ♪
♪ Oh you gonna let it all hang out ♪
♪ 肥臀女孩你维持了摇滚世界的运行 ♪
♪ Fat bottomed girls you make the rockin' world go round ♪
代我向乐队问好
Say hi to the boys for me.
♪ 肥臀女孩你维持了摇滚世界的运行 ♪
♪ Fat bottomed girls you make the rockin' world go round ♪
我会的  爱你
I will. Love you.
再见  弗雷迪  我爱你
Bye, Freddie. I love you.
♪ 跨上你的自行车开始骑吧 ♪
♪ Get on your bikes and ride ♪
男厕
♪ 骑吧牛仔 ♪
♪ Ride 'em cowboy ♪
♪ 来吧  留下 ♪
♪ Come on, stay ♪
♪ 我就喜欢这样 ♪
♪ That's the way I like ♪
♪ 骑吧 ♪
♪ You ride ♪
♪ 很好 ♪
♪ Alright ♪
皇后乐队
大家好
Hello.
-你迟到了  -有吗
- You're late. - Am I?
我们给你留了座位
We saved you a seat.
-真棒  -好了  既然大家都到了
- Lovely. - Okay. So, now that we're all here...
吉姆  这位是雷·福斯特
Jim, this is Ray Foster.
-雷  这位是乐队律师吉姆·比奇  -你好
- Ray, this is the band's lawyer, Jim Beach. - Hello.
你不要再那么喊他了
You must stop calling him that.
那是他的名字
That's his name.
不  我们不能一直叫他"吉姆·比奇"[海滩]
No, we cannot keep calling him "Jim Beach."
那太荒唐了  更不用说还无聊至极
No, that's absurd, not to mention, unspeakably boring.
迈阿密
Miami.
从现在开始  我赐名予你"迈阿密海滩"
From now on, I dub thee "Miami Beach."
太阳总是在身后落下  是吗
The sun always sets behind you, doesn't it?
在迈阿密海滩上
On Miami Beach.
好吧
Hmm, right.
既然大家都有了认可的名字
Now that everybody's got an acceptable name...
我们开始谈正事  听着...
let's get to it. Look...
我们真的需要一些特别的东西
we just really need something special.
更多热门歌曲
More hits...
像《杀手女王》那样的
like Killer Queen...
只不过要更宏大
only bigger.
我们创作的不是随便什么小玩意
It's not bloody widgets we're making.
我们不能复制《杀手女王》
We can't just reproduce Killer Queen.
不行
No.
我们能做得更好
We can do better.
歌剧《卡门》
这是歌剧
It's opera.
-歌剧  -歌剧
- Opera! - Opera!
这里好像有回声呢
There seems to be an echo in here.
是这样  我们不想重复自己
See, we don't want to repeat ourselves.
总是一样的模式反反复复
The same formula over and over.
套用模式创作完完全全就浪费时间
Formulas are a complete and utter waste of time.
模式管用
Formulas work.
我们就照模式来吧
Let's stick with the formulas.
我喜欢模式
I like formulas.
我们给专辑起名叫
We'll call the album...
《歌剧之夜》
A Night at the Opera.
你有没有意识到没人真正喜欢歌剧
Are you aware that no one actually likes opera?
我喜欢歌剧
I like opera.
-真的吗  -真的
- Do you? - I do.
别理解错了  亲爱的
No, don't misunderstand, darling.
这会是一张摇滚专辑
It's a rock and roll record...
只不过加了一些歌剧元素
with the scale of opera...
一些希腊悲剧的伤情
the pathos of Greek tragedy...
一些莎士比亚的睿智
the wit of Shakespeare...
一些音乐剧中无拘无束的快乐
the unbridled joy of musical theater.
-是一种音乐体验  -可不嘛
- It's a musical experience. - Yeah.
而不仅仅是另一张专辑
Rather than just another record.
而是一种普世的东西...
Something for everyone...
一种...
something...
一种让大家觉得是属于他们的东西
Something that will make people feel belongs to them.
我们将融合不同流派  打破界限
We'll mix genres, we'll cross boundaries...
如果我们想的话  就算是说方言也行
we'll speak in bloody tongues if we want to.
没有哪一种音乐风格能概括我们
There's no musical ghetto that can contain us.
-没错  -没人知道皇后乐队代表什么
- That's it. - No one knows what Queen means
因为它不只有一种解释
because it doesn't mean one thing.
你怎么看  约翰
What do you think, John?
我...
I...
同意乐队的想法
agree with the band.
你当然会同意了
Of course you do.
你怎么看
How about you, uh...
叫我迈阿密
Miami.
天助勇者
Fortune favors the bold.
当然了  一位您这样的...
Surely, a man of your...
独特品味的绅士
unique taste...
应该不怕冒一点小风险吧
isn't afraid of a little risk?
拜托不要让我后悔这个决定
Please don't make me regret this.
你真有趣
You're fun.
洛克菲尔德农场      年
这是录音棚
Recording studio?
目的是为了排除一切干扰
Well, the idea was to get away from all distractions.
我知道这里跟丽思酒店有天壤之别
Right, I know it's not the Ritz. Not even close.
-罗杰  你住这间  -好吧
- Roger, you're in here. - Right.
弗雷迪  这间是你的  最大的一间
Freddie, this is you. Biggest room.
布莱恩  你住那间
Brian, that's you.
约翰  你住楼下
John, you're downstairs.
那么...
And...
这里都是你的  约翰
this is all yours, John.
房间小一些就不那么冷
Smaller rooms don't get nearly as cold.
好吧
Okay.
真是太棒了
Oh, that's really good.
♪ 一生挚爱  你伤害了我 ♪
♪ Love of my life, you've hurt me ♪
♪ 你伤了我的心 ♪
♪ You've broken my heart ♪
♪ 又离我而去 ♪
♪ And now you leave me ♪
♪ 一生挚爱  你难道不明白 ♪
♪ Love of my life, can't you see? ♪
♪ 快回来  快回来 ♪
♪ Bring it back, bring it back ♪
♪ 别离开我 ♪
♪ Don't take it away from me ♪
♪ 因为你不知道 ♪
♪ Because you don't know ♪
♪ 你对我有多重要 ♪
♪ What it means to me ♪
真动听
It's beautiful.
这首歌叫什么
What's it called?
《一生挚爱》  我写给玛丽的
Love of My Life. I wrote it for Mary.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
别误会  保罗
Don't misunderstand, Paul.
玛丽对我的了解  是别人无法企及的
Mary knows me in a way that no one else ever will.
我了解你  弗雷迪·默丘里
I know you, Freddie Mercury.
你是这么觉得的吗
Is that what you think?
不  你不了解我
Oh, no, you don't know me.
你只能看到你想看到的
You just see what you want to see.
我们一起工作  仅此而已
We work together. That's all.
我把全副身心都投入到这首歌里了
I put my heart and soul into this song.
没人怀疑那一点
No one is disputing that.
你不喜欢它
And you don't like it
是因为你想让自己的歌被收录进专辑
because you want your songs on the album!
-不是那样的  罗杰  -那是哪样
- It's not that, Roger. - Then what is it?
《我爱上了我的车》
I'm in Love with My Car.
可能不够劲
Maybe it's not strong enough?
"不够劲"是什么意思
What does that even mean, "Not strong enough"?
我知道我来晚了  我错过了什么
I know I'm late. What did I miss?
我们在讨论罗杰那首写车的歌
Discussing Roger's car song.
够不够劲  我就问你
Is it strong enough? That's all I'm asking.
要是就我一个人这么想  那我道歉
If I'm on my own here, then I apologize.
那你的新歌怎么样了
How does your new song go, then, hmm?
"你叫我甜心
"You call me sweet...
我就像美味芝士一样"
"Like I'm some kind of cheese."
挺好的呀
It's good.
"我的手摸到你的注油枪"
"When my hand's on your grease gun..."
真是微妙啊
That's very subtle, isn't it?
那是比喻  布莱恩
It's a metaphor, Brian.
就是有点奇怪  罗杰
It's just a bit weird, Roger.
你到底在对那辆车做什么
What exactly are you doing with that car?
孩子们  别闹了
Children, please.
我们当然可以互相残杀
We could all murder each other...
但这样一来  谁去录专辑呢
but then who would be left to record this album?
数据表明  大多数乐队的结局并不是过气
Statistically speaking, most bands don't fail,
而是成员闹翻了
they break up.
你说这种话用意何在
Why the hell would you say something like that?
罗杰  这支乐队只容得下
Roger, there's only room in this band
一个能闹能作的人
for one hysterical queen.
你知道你为什么愤怒吧  罗杰
You know why you're angry, Roger?
为什么
Why?
因为你知道你的歌不够劲
'Cause you know your song isn't strong enough.
-不够...  -这下够了吗
- Not... - Is that strong enough?
那这样呢
What about that?
不许扔咖啡机
Not the coffee machine!
♪ 再见  所有人啊 ♪
♪ Goodbye, everybody ♪
♪ 我必须走 ♪
♪ I've got to go ♪
♪ 不得不离你们而去面对真相 ♪
♪ Gotta leave you all behind and face the truth ♪
♪ 妈妈 ♪
♪ Mama ♪
♪ 我不想死 ♪
♪ I don't wanna die ♪
♪ 有时我宁愿从未降生于世 ♪
♪ I sometimes wish I'd never been born at all ♪
然后呢
What next?
真的很棒
That was pretty damn good.
太好了  我爱这段
Brilliant. I love that.
按按钮再说  弗雷迪
Press the button, Freddie.
我知道  我知道它在哪
I know, I know where it is.
我知道  喂喂
I know where... Knock, knock.
好
Good.
很好
It's good. Um...
你弹着感觉就像这段是你写的一样
You know, play it like you wrote it.
确实是啊  那段就是我写的
Well, I did. I wrote that part.
逗你呢
Taking the piss.
好吧  满意了吗
Okay. Are you happy?
我觉得好美
I think it's beautiful.
几乎完美
It's almost perfect.
几乎
Almost?
对  让它更摇滚一些
Yes, give it more rock and roll.
这个随时都可以  弗雷
I'm always up for that, Fred.
全身心投入
Put your body into it.
好  好的
Right. Okay.
全身心投入  我懂了
Put my body into it. I got it.
不是那样
Not like that.
-不  我懂  我懂  -好
- No, I got it. I got it. - All right.
-注入灵魂  对吗  -多走点心
- Bit more soul, yeah? - Give it more heart.
我会的  可以开始了吗
I'll do that. We good to go?
罗伊  可以了吗
Roy, you good?
然后就到歌剧那段了
Oh, and then there's the operatic section.
你会喜欢的
You're gonna love it.
歌剧那段
The operatic section?
-我知道  很疯狂  -我爱那段  弗雷  很爱
- I know, it sounds crazy. - I love it, Fred. I love it.
我不知道会怎样  可能会搞砸
I don't know. It could be a flop.
-也可能会成功  -我爱那段
- It could work. - I love it!
我们还有什么可失去的呢
What have we got to lose?
什么都没有
Nothing.
你说得对
If you say so.
好了  开始吧
Okay, let's go.
迪迪
Deacy.
♪ 有时我宁愿从未降生于世 ♪
♪I sometimes wish I'd never been born at all♪
怎么样
How was that?
-弗雷迪  -再高点
- Freddie? - Higher.
你能再高点吗
Can you go a bit higher?
再高就超越人类听力极限了
If I go any higher, only dogs will hear me.
试试看
Try.
弗雷迪说的  抱歉
Freddie's note. Sorry.
继续  继续录
Go on, roll the tape.
第24次叠录"弗雷的唱段"
Overdub 24 of "Fred's Thing."
♪ 电闪和雷鸣  非常非常可怕 ♪
♪ Thunderbolt and lightning, very, very fright'ning me ♪
♪ 伽利略  伽利略  伽利略  费加罗  贵族们 ♪
♪ Galileo, Galileo, Galileo Figaro magnifico ♪
怎么样
How was that?
-好点了吗  -再高点
- Better? - Higher.
天啊  你还要我再唱多少遍"伽利略"
Jesus! How many more "Galileos" do you want?
弗雷迪想再多叠几层音
Freddie wants to do a few more overdubs.
我们还有带子可用吗
Do we even have any tape left?
我确实得说一句  带子快被磨穿了
I do have to say the tape is wearing out.
不能再叠了
It can't take much more.
我们也耗不起了
Yeah, we can't afford much more.
我们已经落后进度三周了
We're already three weeks over schedule.
第26次叠录"弗雷的唱段"
Dub 26 of "Fred's Thing."
♪ 电闪和雷鸣  非常非常可怕 ♪
♪ Thunderbolt and lightning, very, very fright'ning me ♪
再来一次  再来一次
One more, one more.
♪ 伽利略  伽利略  伽利略  费加罗  贵族们 ♪
♪ Galileo, Galileo, Galileo Figaro magnifico ♪
再来
One more.
Again.
继续
Go on, roll the track.
伽利略到底是谁
Who even is Galileo?
我的蛋都要提到胸腔里了
My nuts feel like they're in my chest right now.
-行了吗  -可以了
- Are we done? - That's it.
♪ 我只是个可怜没人爱的孩子 ♪
♪ I'm just a poor boy and nobody loves me ♪
他爱你
He loves you.
♪ 他只是穷人家的可怜孩子 ♪
♪ He's just a poor boy from a poor family ♪
这就对了
That's it.
♪ 从魔鬼手中救他一命吧 ♪
♪ Spare him his life from this monstrosity ♪
真好听  爱
It's beautiful! Love it!
♪ 来得快去得也快 ♪
♪ Easy come easy go will you let me go ♪
♪ 真主啊 ♪
♪ Bismillah ♪
♪ 不  我们绝不放你走 ♪
♪ No! We will not let you go ♪
♪ 冲我来  冲我来 ♪
♪ For me for me for me ♪
♪ 什么都无所谓 ♪
♪ Nothing really matters ♪
♪ 我真的什么都无所谓 ♪
♪ Nothing really matters to me ♪
♪ 无论风吹向何方 ♪
♪ Anyway the wind blows ♪
天啊
Christ.
其实  我不太确定
Well... I'm not entirely sure...
当初你们答应做的专辑是这样的
that's the album you promised us.
不  这比我们当初答应的专辑更好
No, it's better than the album we promised you.
比任何人
It's better than any album
答应给你做的专辑都更好  亲爱的
anyone's ever promised you, darling.
这就是杰作
It's a bloody masterpiece.
-天啊  -这专辑很棒  雷
- Christ. - It is a good album, Ray.
我们更喜欢称之为"杰作"
We prefer "Masterpiece."
它花了那么多钱  还有...
It's expensive, and as for...
"波西米亚"
"Bohemian..."
"狂想曲"
Rhapsody.
狂想曲  那是什么
Rhapsody. What is that?
-是一种史诗  -这也太长了  足足六分钟
- It's an epic poem. - It goes on forever. Six bloody minutes.
要是你觉得六分钟长  那你妻子也太可怜了
I pity your wife if you think six minutes is forever.
你猜怎么着
And do you know what?
我们要把它作为单曲发行
We're going to release it as our single.
不可能  超过三分钟的...
Not possible. Anything over three minutes...
而且电台也不会安排播放的  不用再说了
and the radio stations won't program it, period.
还有  这究竟唱的是什么
And what on earth is it about, anyway?
小丑
Scaramouche?
伽利略
Galileo?
还有什么乱七八糟的"以兹玛拉"
And all that "Ismillah" business!
还是"以实玛拉"
"Ishmillah"?
是诵真主之名
Bismillah.
对
Oh, aye.
诵真主之名
Bismillah.
到底是唱什么的  什么诵真主之名
What's it about, anyway? Bloody Bismillah?
真正的诗是写给听众的
True poetry is for the listener.
要是一切都直白明了  神秘感就被毁了
It ruins the mystery if everything's explained.
但是销量不会被毁
Seldom ruins sales.
一首歌的正常时长是三分钟
Three minutes is the standard.
约翰
John.
好吧  我们需要电台
Yeah, we need radio.
标准确实是三分钟  我不得不同意雷说的
Format is three minutes, I have to agree with Ray.
我觉得单曲用《一生挚爱》比较好
I actually think the single's Love of My Life.
不行
No.
好吧  那约翰的歌呢
Okay, how about John's song...
《你是我最好的朋友》  怎么样
You're My Best Friend? You know?
"你让我活下去"
"Ooh, you make me live."
朗朗上口  更劲
Catchy, stronger.
那《我爱上了我的车》呢
What about I'm in Love with My Car?
你开玩笑吧  天啊
You're joking! Oh, Jesus.
我爱这首
I love it.
这种歌
Well, that's the kind of song...
青少年会在车里开大音量播放
teenagers can crank up the volume in their car...
边听边猛摇头
and bang their heads to.
他们听《波西米亚狂想曲》就不会这么干
Bohemian Rhapsody will never be that song.
乐队决定了  《波西米亚狂想曲》
It's a band decision, Bohemian Rhapsody.
-就这样  -《你是我最好的朋友》
- That's it. - You're My Best Friend...
出钱的人是我
and it's my money.
《波狂》  没得商量
Bo-Rap, period.
不然我们走人
Or we walk.
《麦克阿瑟公园》时长七分钟  风靡一时
MacArthur Park was seven minutes long. It was a hit.
我不是想讨论波西米亚什么什么的
Look, I'm not arguing Bohemian whatever's...
-音乐性  -狂想曲
- musicianship. - ...Rhapsody.
但是电台绝对不会答应播放
But there's no way in hell the station will play...
一首六分钟的惨兮兮的伪歌剧歌曲
a 6-minute quasi-operatic dirge...
唱着一堆听不懂的歌词
comprised of nonsense words!
"诵真主之名"  胡扯
Bismillah? Bullshit!
做这张唱片花的是我的钱  所以得听我的
I paid for this record, so I say what goes!
我们没有法律追索权吗
Have we no legal recourse on this?
雷
Ray...
《月之暗面》是你发行的吧  对不对
you did Dark Side of the Moon, didn't you?
对
I did.
我非常喜欢那张专辑
Yeah, I absolutely love that record.
从法律角度说  没有
Legally, no.
他牢牢控制着你们
No, he's got all your balls in a vice.
当然了  在舆论的法庭上就是另一码事了
It's a different matter in the court of public opinion, of course.
雷·福斯特在音乐业内赫赫有名  但是
Ray Foster's a giant name in the music industry, but...
对普通人来说
to the average person...
一提起皇后乐队的名字
Say the name Queen, on the other hand...
大家会竖起耳朵
ears prick up.
我们选《你是我最好的朋友》
We're going with You're My Best Friend.
-说定了  -不  我们清楚哪首最好
- Done. - No. We know what we have,
即便你有眼无珠
even if you don't.
那首叫《波西米亚狂想曲》
It's called Bohemian Rhapsody.
你将永远被称为失去了皇后乐队的人
You will forever be known as the man who lost Queen.
真是一群神经质的艺术家
Temperamental artists, eh?
他们清楚得很  自己受合同约束
They're well aware they're tied to a contract...
但谁知道歌手
but who knows what goes on...
不可思议的脑袋里在想什么
inside the inscrutable mind of the recording artist?
记住我这句话
Mark these words.
要是他们不小心点
If they're not careful...
等到今年年末
by the end of the year...
皇后乐队将无人知晓
no one will know the name Queen.
天啊
Christ!
你可以从我们的版税里扣
You can take that out of our royalties!
-傻逼  -杂种
- Twat! - Wanker!
去你的金唱片
You can shove your gold disks!
你犯下大错了  福斯特
You made a mistake, Foster!
混蛋
Arsehole!
你们再也别想出金唱片了
You'll never have a gold disk...
这群庸才
you medium talent!
想想我可是和亨德里克斯合作过的人
And to think I worked with Hendrix.
被誉为世界最伟大的吉他手
今天来到演播室的是
In the studio today...
直播中
歌手弗雷迪·默丘里
...singer Frederick Mercury!
你今天给我们带来了什么
So what have you got today for us?
我们能有幸听一听你的新专辑吗
We got a little taste of the new record?
我真的不该在这儿放的
I'm really not supposed to.
禁果吗  别诱惑我
Oh, forbidden fruit? Don't tempt me!
-《我爱上了我的车》 -另一面
- "I'm in Love with My Car!" - Other side.
《波西米亚狂想曲》
"Bohemian Rhapsody."
我还真不知道弗雷迪跟肯尼这么熟
I didn't know Freddie knew Kenny so well.
BBC不愿意播放
The BBC won't play it.
我也不知道
Nor did I.
其实  没人愿意在电台上放那首歌
In fact, no one will play it on the radio...
所以EMI不会发行这首
so EMI won't release it.
这首歌有什么问题
What's wrong with this song?
什么问题都没有
Nothing's wrong with it at all.
只不过它长达六分钟
Except that it's six minutes long.
六分钟
Six minutes?
要是放这首歌  你就绝对是疯了
You'd have to be mad to play it.
百分之百是疯了
Oh, you'd have to be bonkers.
-我绝对不允许  -我们来听听
- I positively forbid it. - Let's hear it.
女士们和小姐们
Ladies and ladies...
首都电台
a Capital Radio exclusive...
独家首播
for the first time ever...
《波西米亚狂想曲》
Bohemian Rhapsody!
♪ 这是现实生活吗 ♪
♪ Is this the real life ♪
♪ 这只是幻想吗 ♪
♪ Is this just fantasy ♪
♪ 被困于山崩之中 ♪
♪ Caught in a landslide ♪
矫揉造作
绕圈子  无意义
装成齐伯林飞艇乐队
♪ 无法逃离现实 ♪
♪ No escape from reality ♪
他们用声效
可惜  不是写十四行诗的料
皇后乐队急于巩固他们的"严肃性"
这首歌应该永远沉到海底  从此消失
♪ 睁开双眼 ♪
♪ Open your eyes ♪
一首厚脸皮大杂烩
自夸过头  太长了
无聊的拼贴
♪ 抬头仰望天空 ♪
♪ Look up to the skies and see ♪
没有哪段曲调或歌词能让人听懂
空洞无物  没有真情实感的堆砌
没有副歌  六分钟内尝试至少六种迥然不同的风格
堪称完美
♪ 你以为能扔石头吐口水羞辱我 ♪
♪ So you think you can stone me and spit in my eye ?
爱丁堡
♪ 你以为能爱我然后丢下我等死 ♪
♪ So you think you can love me and leave me to die ?
♪ 宝贝 ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ 别这样对我 ♪
♪ Can't do this to me, baby ♪
♪ 快点逃 ♪
♪ Just gotta get out ♪
♪ 快点逃出去 ♪
♪ Just gotta get right outta here ♪
观众多爱他啊
How much do they love him?
爱不够
Can't get enough.
♪ 什么都无所谓 ♪
♪ Nothing really matters ♪
♪ 谁都明白 ♪
♪ Anyone can see ♪
♪ 什么都无所谓 ♪
♪ Nothing really matters ♪
♪ 我真的什么都无所谓 ♪
♪ Nothing really matters to me ♪
♪ 无论风吹向何方 ♪
♪ Any way the wind blows ♪
利物浦
Now I'm here
♪ Here I stand ♪
底特律
东京
珀斯
♪ Look around around around around around ♪
格拉斯哥
伦敦
纽约
♪ But you won't see me ♪
波士顿
大阪
圣莫妮卡
♪ Now I'm here ♪
匹兹堡
悉尼
芝加哥
里约
♪ I'm just a ♪
♪ I'm just a new man ♪
♪ Yes you made me live again ♪
汤姆  杰瑞  能听见吗
Tom, Jerry, can you hear me?
弗雷迪  我什么时候能见到你
Freddie, when do I get to see you?
我马上就回家了  亲爱的
I'll be home soon, darling.
你能不能让罗密欧接电话
Will you put Romeo on the phone
我好跟他说我想他
so I can tell him I miss him?
你想我吗
Do you miss me?
好傻的问题
What a stupid question.
当然想了
Of course I do.
我爱你
I love you.
晚安
Good night.
早  老大
Morning, boss.
把这摊收拾干净  把你的朋友打发走
Clean this mess up and get rid of your friend.
穿好衣服
Get dressed.
布莱恩说
According to Brian...
这是商演史上观众最多的一场演出
it was the largest paying audience in history.
整晚
The whole night...
我之前不知道他们懂不懂我表达的东西
I didn't know if they understood a thing I was saying.
然后
And then...
♪ 一生挚爱  你伤害了我 ♪
♪ Love of my life, you've hurt me ♪
♪ 你伤了我的心 ♪
♪ You've broken my heart ♪
♪ 又离我而去 ♪
♪ And now you leave me ♪
♪ 一生挚爱  你难道不明白 ♪
♪ Love of my life, can't you see ♪
♪ 快回来  快回来 ♪
♪ Bring it back, bring it back ♪
♪ 别离开我 ♪
♪ Don't take it away from me ♪
所有人都在唱
They're all singing.
几千人
Thousands of them.
都在为你唱
All singing to you.
因为这是真的
Because it's true.
弗雷迪  怎么了
Freddie, what's wrong?
有些事不太对劲  已经有段时间了
Something's been wrong for a while now.
说吧
Say it.
说
我考虑了很久
I've been thinking about it a lot.
我觉得我是双性恋
I think I'm bisexual.
弗雷迪  你是同性恋
Freddie, you're gay.
我知道了一段时间了
I've known for a while now.
我只是不想承认
I just didn't want to admit it.
有趣的是  我总是碰上这种事
It's funny, really. This is what I always settle for.
"我爱你  但是..."
"I love you, but..."
"我爱你  玛丽  但是我需要空间"
"I love you, Mary, but I need space."
"我爱你  玛丽  但是我遇到了另一个人"
"I love you, Mary, but I've met someone else."
现在呢  "我爱你  但是我是..."
And now, "I love you, but I'm..."
这次是最难接受的  因为甚至都不能怪你
And this is the hardest, because it's not even your fault.
不  别拿下来
No, don't take it off.
别拿下来
Don't take it off.
你答应过我永远都不拿下来的
You promised me you'd never take it off.
你想从我这里得到什么
What do you want from me?
我要你的一切
Almost everything.
我要你在我的生活中
I want you in my life.
为什么
Why?
我们彼此信任
We believe in each other.
那意味着一切
And that's everything.
对于我们而言
For us.
你的生活会非常艰难
Your life is going to be very difficult.
伦敦      年
你觉得怎样
What do you think?
更基了
Gay-er?
不是胡子  亲爱的  是房子
Not this, darling, the house.
是不是很棒
Isn't it amazing?
玛丽已经搬到隔壁了
Mary's already moved in next door,
这样她可以看看猫  看看我
so she can visit the cats and me.
每只猫都有自己的房间
Each cat will have his own room.
黛利拉的房间在厨房边
Delilah's by the kitchen...
米可在隔壁
Miko's next door.
蒂芙尼  奥斯卡  罗密欧  都住楼上
Tiffany, Oscar, Romeo, all upstairs.
莉莉的房间比这间还大  它被宠坏了
Lilly's room is even larger than this one! Spoilt thing.
我觉得回声不够明显
Well, I'm not sure the echo is quite pronounced enough.
我就知道你会喜欢
Oh, I knew you'd appreciate it.
留下吃晚饭吧
Stay for dinner.
你想吃什么都行
Anything you fancy.
不行  得回家陪妻子孩子
I can't. Wife, kids, you know.
当然了
Of course.
来嘛  我们坐地上吃  很干净
Well, come on. We'll eat off the floor. It's clean enough.
改天吧  弗雷
Another time, Fred.
-喂  -玛丽
- Hello? - Mary.
-嗨  -你好  吾爱
- Hi. - Hello, my love.
我需要你帮我做件事
I need you to do something for me.
但别问问题
But you can't ask any questions.
弗雷迪  这次你又要做什么
Freddie, what are you doing this time?
不  我刚说  你不能问问题
No, I just told you... you can't ask any questions.
好吧
Right.
你去卧室窗前
I want you to go to your bedroom window.
望向窗外
Look out of it.
-你看到我了吗  -看到了
- Do you see me? - Yes, I do see you.
你也这样做
Now, you do the same.
别关灯
Keep yours on.
过来喝一杯吧
Come have a drink.
-现在吗  -就现在
- Now? - Right now.
很晚了  弗雷迪
It's late, Freddie.
来嘛
Come on.
求你了
Please.
你那里有喝的吗
Do you have something to drink?
有吧
I suppose.
去拿吧  给自己倒上一杯
Go get it. Pour yourself something.
给你自己倒一杯喝的  亲爱的
Pour yourself a drink, darling.
倒好了吗
Do you have it?
好了
Yes.
干杯
Cheers.
敬你  吾爱
To you, my love.
敬你  弗雷迪
To you, Freddie.
晚安
Good night.
-喂  -保罗
- Hello? - Paul.
弗雷迪
Freddie?
宝贝  我想办派对
Sweetheart, I want to throw a party.
好  你想要请谁
Okay. Who do you want to invite?
人们
People.
你摇一摇长着怪人的树
I want you to shake the freak tree
把掉在地上的人都请来
and invite anyone who plops to the ground.
矮人  巨人
Dwarfs and giants...
魔法师  祖鲁人  柔术演员
magicians, Zulu tribesmen, contortionists...
吞火者
fire eaters...
神父
and priests.
我们需要告解
We're going to need to confess.
Crazy Little Thing Called Love
♪ This thing called love ♪
♪ I just can't handle it ♪
♪ I must get round to it ♪
给我倒满好吗  特里克西
Fill me up, will you, Trixie?
太棒了  弗雷  你超越了自己
Marvelous, Fred! You've outdone yourself!
♪ I ain't ready ♪
谢谢  约翰  真高兴你喜欢
Thank you, John. I'm so glad you love it!
♪ Crazy little thing called love ♪
他们说钱买不到快乐  宝贝们
Mmm. They say money can't buy happiness, darlings!
但你确实可以散财
But it does allow you to give it away!
你和保罗相处得很不错嘛
I see you and Paul are getting along quite well.
他现在是特里克西
He's Trixie now...
因为他总爱搞事
'cause he's always up to something.
告诉我  罗
So, tell me, Rog...
一辆车最性感的部分是哪里
what's the sexiest part of a car?
瞧瞧  瞧瞧
Well, well, well!
陛下
Ah, your majesty!
不  我不是陛下
No, I'm not her majesty!
我们都是陛下  宝贝们
We're her majesty, darlings!
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers! - Cheers!
-谢谢  宝贝们  -罗
- Thank you, my loves! - Rog.
玛丽呢
Where's Mary?
她不喜欢这种场合吧  弗雷迪
It's not exactly her scene, is it, Freddie?
真棒  是不是
Fabulous, isn't it?
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
你们看上去越来越像了
You're starting to look like each other.
那有什么不好  布莱恩
What's wrong with that, Brian?
你应该是摇滚乐队的一员  弗雷迪
You're supposed to be in a rock band, Freddie.
而不是村民乐队的
Not the Village People.
一个成员全部都是同性恋的组合
改天考虑一下理发吧
You might want to think about cutting your hair one day.
绝不  我生来如此
Never. I was born like this.
快来
Come on!
-我们跳舞吧  -太好了
- Let's dance! - Yes!
我不跳舞  弗雷迪
I don't dance, Freddie.
要跳舞我得让自己更醉一些
I need a few more of these for that.
这是我的派对  我命令你们跳舞
It's my party, and I demand you dance!
我们该走了
We should go.
我下敕令
By royal decree!
我们打算撤了实际上
We're gonna go, actually.
天啊  你们真无趣
Oh, God! You're dull.
要是你们再无趣些  就变成迪迪了
If you were any more dull, you'd be Deacy.
你在抱怨什么
What are you complaining about?
你有你的小宠物陪着呢
You've got your little pet.
没错
I have...
而且他忠心耿耿
and he's loyal.
忠诚太重要了  你觉得呢  多米尼克
Loyalty's so important. Don't you think, Dominique?
小心点  弗雷
Careful, Fred.
-我们走  -你们要去哪
- Let's go. - Where you going?
回家
Home.
开玩笑而已
Just a joke.
弗雷迪  有时候你就是一个彻头彻尾的混蛋
Freddie, sometimes you're a total prick.
-晚安  -布莱恩
- Good night. - Brian.
别管他们
Forget them.
快来  你的宾客们等着呢
Come on! Your guests are waiting.
他们都想见见水星默丘里
They all want a little Mercury in their cup.
快来
Come on.
好了
All right!
亲爱的们
My darlings...
终于到了
the time has finally come...
一醉方休的时候
to get absolutely... shit-faced!
先生  我的白粉在哪
Senor, where's my marching powder?
你可够胆大的
You've got a set of balls.
帮我拿杯酒  你就知道了
Go fetch me a drink and find out.
我今晚是为你工作没错
I may work for you tonight...
但你再摸我一下  我就锤死你
but put your hands on me again, and I'll thump you.
明白了吗
Got it?
真抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
无意冒犯  抱歉
I didn't mean to offend you. I'm sorry.
我不会再那样了  好吗
I won't do that again, all right?
我给你拿瓶啤酒
Let me get you a beer.
喝瓶啤酒也无妨
I wouldn't mind a beer.
你能告诉我啤酒放在哪里吗
Can you just tell me where we keep them?
你真英俊
You're very handsome.
我喜欢穿制服的男人
I love a man in uniform.
我也是
So do I.
你的朋友们都离你而去了
So, all your friends have left you alone.
他们不是我的朋友
They're not my friends.
并不是
Not really.
我只是用他们来转移注意力
Just distraction.
从什么上转移
From what?
那些空虚的时刻吧  我猜
The in-between moments, I suppose.
它们让人难以忍受
I find them intolerable.
所有的...
All of the...
你以为已经甩在身后的黑暗又再次袭来
darkness you thought you left behind comes creeping back in.
我懂你说的
I know what you mean.
真的吗
Really?
那要怎么办呢
What is it that you do with them?
和真正的朋友共度
Spend them with real friends.
你好像很需要一个朋友
You look like you could use a friend.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我也喜欢你  弗雷迪
I like you, too, Freddie.
等你决心喜欢自己了再来找我
Come and find me when you decide you like yourself.
至少告诉我你的名字吧
Can I have your name at least?
吉姆·赫顿
It's Jim Hutton.
-晚安  吉姆  -晚安  弗雷迪
- Good night, Jim. - Good night, Freddie.
或者应该说早安
Or should I say good morning?
我要一条新的船
I want a new boat.
这是我的  这个
This one is for me. This one.
你不是说我们要去见他吗
Didn't you say we were going to see him?
-我还有一个小时  -等等  这个怎么样
- I've got an hour left. - Wait. What about this one?
不  我觉得我们还是选那个
No, I think we'll still make that.
大小很合适
It's a good size.
去他的
Screw him.
大家都到鼓台上来
Everyone up on the drum risers!
-上鼓台  -快来
- Up on the drum risers. - Come on!
谢谢  克丽丝  你真热情
Thank you, Chrissie. Showing some enthusiasm.
-家属也过去吗  布莱恩  -我
- Wives and everyone, Brian? - Me?
对  快  约翰  所有人
Yes! Come on, John. Everyone.
-我不等了  -走吧
- I'm not waiting any longer. - Let's go.
上去
Get up.
-贝斯  -不  用不着拿
- Bass? - No, you don't need it.
上去
Get up.
-快点  罗  抓紧时间  -好嘛
- Come on, Rog, take your time. - All right.
这是干什么
What's this about?
还记得我们上次演唱会吗
You remember our last concert?
观众对着我们  唱我们的歌
The crowd were singing our songs back to us.
震耳欲聋  但感觉非常棒
I mean, it was deafening, but it was wonderful.
他们成了我们的演出的一部分
They're becoming a part of our show.
我想鼓励这种行为  所以
I want to encourage that, so...
我有个想法  能让他们更多地参与进来
I've got an idea to involve them a little bit more.
先这样
Let's start with this.
按这个节奏跺脚
Stamp to this beat.
天才
Genius.
谢谢你  约翰
Thank you, John.
来吧
Come on.
很好
Good.
现在大家在第三拍的时候拍手
Now, I want you to clap on the third beat.
不要加快速度
Don't speed up.
罗  保持这个速度
Rog, keep that time.
普兰特没来吗
No Prenter?
挺少见你不带着你的克隆人
It's unusual to see you without your clone.
挺少见你嘴这么毒
It's unusual seeing you be so bitchy.
一般是我
It's usually me.
速度保持住了  罗  很好
Ah, you kept time, Rog. Good.
现在这是怎么回事
What's going on?
你要是准时来不就知道了
You'd know if you were on time.
我是个表演者  亲爱的  不是瑞士列车员
I'm a performer, darling, not a Swiss train conductor.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
又一次
Again.
行吧
All right.
能不能劳驾你告诉我
Now, will you please tell me
为什么你们一种乐器也不用
why you're not playing any instruments?
我想给听众一首他们能演奏的歌
I wanna give the audience a song that they can perform.
让他们加入到乐队中来
All right? Let them be part of the band.
那他们能做什么呢
So, what can they do?
想象一下
Imagine...
数千观众
thousands of people...
一齐这么做
doing this in unison.
怎么样
Well?
那歌词呢
What's the lyric?
♪ 你这孩子喜欢闹出大动静 ♪
♪ Buddy, you're a boy make a big noise ♪
麦迪逊广场花园
♪ 在街头玩耍  盼望有天成为大人物 ♪
♪ Playing in the street gonna be a big man some day ♪
麦迪逊广场花园
♪ 你脸上蹭了泥 ♪
♪ You got mud on your face ♪
♪ 真是丢人 ♪
♪ You big disgrace ♪
♪ 到处踢你那铁罐 ♪
♪ Kickin' your can all over the place ♪
♪ 还唱着 ♪
♪ Singin' ♪
♪ 我们要让你摇滚起来 ♪
♪ We will, we will rock you. ♪
♪ 你现在血气方刚  是个硬汉 ♪
♪ Buddy, you're a young man, hard man ♪
♪ 在大街上嚷嚷着 ♪
♪ Shouting in the street ♪
♪ 有一天总会征服这个世界 ♪
♪ Gonna take on the world some day ♪
♪ 你脸上挂了彩 ♪
♪ You got blood on your face ♪
♪ 真是丢人 ♪
♪ You big disgrace ♪
♪ 到处挥舞着你的旗帜 ♪
♪ Wavin' your banner all over the place ♪
♪ 我们要让你摇滚起来 ♪
♪ We will, we will rock you. ♪
♪ 一起来 ♪
♪ Singin' ♪
♪ 我们要让你摇滚起来 ♪
♪ We will, we will rock you. ♪
很好
Yeah!
♪ 你现在衰老又可怜 ♪
♪ Buddy, you're an old man, poor man ♪
♪ 用双眼向人恳求 ♪
♪ Pleading with your eyes ♪
♪ 有一天能得到些许平静 ♪
♪ Gonna get you some peace someday ♪
♪ 你脸上蹭了泥  真是丢人 ♪
♪ You got mud on your face big disgrace ♪
♪ 最好有人来让你摆正位置 ♪
♪ Somebody better put you back into your place ♪
来吧
Do it!
♪ 我们要让你摇滚起来 ♪
♪ We will, we will rock you. ♪
我感觉好像尝了一口大苹果[纽约城]
All right! I feel like taking a bite out of the Big Apple!
谁想来尝尝我
Who wants to take a bite out of me?
好了  来和我一起唱
All right, play with me now.
银河系  星球
我从没见过任何人像这样和观众互动
Never seen anyone interact with a crowd like that.
比其他任何乐队都要浩大  不觉得吗
Bigger than any band, don't you think?
我是说  这皇后乐队
I mean, Queen...
又能红多久呢
how long can that last?
他和你说什么了吗
Did he say something to you?
没有明说
Not explicitly.
但哥伦比亚唱片公司有兴趣
But we've had some interest from CBS Records...
做个单飞
about a solo deal.
好大的数目
Well, that's a big number.
那是配得上弗雷迪的数目
That's a Freddie-size number.
你应该去向他提出来
You should be the one to propose it.
你们好  近来如何
Hi, guys. How's it going?
-挺好  -一切都好
- Good. - Everything's great.
约翰  再来一杯吗
John, another drink?
不用了  谢谢
Er, no, I'm fine.
这是您的可乐  马上就来
Here's the Coke. Coming right up.
-弗雷迪  -你在这儿
- Freddie. - Oh, there you are.
天啊  弗雷迪  放我下来
Oh, God! Freddie! Put me down!
你太棒了
You were brilliant.
那是因为我知道你在看我呀
Ah, that's only because I knew you were watching.
我想你了
I've missed you.
我们得好好聊一场
We have so much to catch up on.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
这是我男朋友  大卫
This is my boyfriend, David.
大卫  这是弗雷迪
David, this is Freddie.
真是一场盛大的演出
Magnificent show.
谢谢
Thank you.
过奖了  非常感谢
It's so kind of you, I appreciate it.
太感谢了
Thank you so much.
你的戒指呢
Where's your ring?
我只是不想戴着这么贵重的东西出门
I just didn't want to travel with something so valuable.
弗雷迪  这里有些人你得会会
Freddie, there are some people here for you to see.
你答应过会去打个招呼的
You promised you'd say hello.
我答应过吗
Oh, did I?
我们该走了
We should go.
我们很快会再见的吧
Will I see you soon?
是的  当然  当然了
Yes, of course. Of course.
很高兴见到你  大卫
It's a pleasure to meet you, David.
我也是
And you.
再次祝贺你
And well done again.
你也是
And you.
再见
Bye.
谢谢你们大老远的跑来
Thank you for coming such a long way.
再见
Bye.
接着有个MTV的采访
Then you've got the MTV interview...
飞到休斯顿做个特别节目
and the plane to Houston for the special.
周五回来
Back here on Friday.
现在听我说
Listen to me now.
你知道去年
Do you know who sold
谁的专辑占全部销量的4%吗
4% of all the records purchased last year?
我说的是全世界
Worldwide?
迈克尔·杰克逊
Michael Jackson.
不是杰克逊五人组
Not the Jackson 5.
迈克尔·杰克逊
Michael Jackson.
我觉得你能比他更强
And I think you could do even better.
其实我这有一份哥伦比亚唱片公司的邀请
In fact, I've had an offer from CBS Records.
这对你来说是一大笔钱  弗雷
It's a lot of money for you, Fred,
我认为你应该考虑一下
and I think you should consider it.
你是要我解散乐队吗
Are you asking me to break up the band?
我只是向你指明单飞会为你带来什么
I'm just pointing out what awaits you if you go solo.
它能让你不再感到沮丧
An end to your frustrations.
我沮丧什么
My frustrations?
保罗
Paul?
我不知道你在说什么  约翰
I don't know what you're talking about, John.
也许是我误解了
Perhaps I misunderstood.
请吩咐  先生
Yes, sir.
靠边停车
Pull over.
停车  靠边停车
Stop the car, pull over.
-滚出去  立刻出去  -搞什么
- Get out. Out now! - What the hell?
从车里滚出去  你被炒了
Get out of this car. You're fired.
-你说什么炒了  -我说让你滚
- What're you talking about, fired? -I said get out.
-弗雷迪  你嗑嗨了  -我说滚出去
- Freddie, you are high! - I said get out!
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
滚  再不滚我就杀了你
Out! Out or I'll kill you!
滚蛋  你这个卑鄙小人
Get out, you treacherous piss flap.
-你脑子不清醒  -你他妈赶紧从我车里出去
- You're not thinking clearly. - Get your ass out of my car now.
滚啊
Get out!
滚
Out!
你他妈出去  滚出去
Get your ass out of my car! Get out!
你身边的小人不是我  弗雷迪
You're firing the wrong snake, Freddie.
你会后悔的
You'll regret it.
你他妈滚
Get your ass out of here!
开车
Drive!
搞什么  一边去
What the hell? Move!
可长点眼吧  我他妈碾死你
Hey, watch it! I'll run your ass over!
一边去
Move!
你对这件事知情吗
Did you know anything about this?
我警告过他别这样的
I warned him against it.
他就是贪婪
Pure greed.
想拆散我的家庭
Tried to break up my family.
我们可以管好乐队
We can manage the band.
我们不需要他
We don't need him.
你对我需要什么又了解多少
What do you know about what I need?
我知道无法融入
I know what it's like...
是什么感觉
not to belong.
一个来自贝尔法斯特  信天主教的同性恋男孩
A queer Catholic boy from Belfast.
你知道吗
You know...
我认为  比起让我做自己  我爸可能
I think my father would rather see me dead...
还更愿意让我死掉
than let me be who I am.
现在由我来照顾你  弗雷迪
I'm gonna take care of you now, Freddie.
如果你允许的话
If you'll let me.
那些皇后乐队的男人们  弗雷迪在隐藏什么  他穿着黑皮裤征服了纽约
弗雷迪身处危险之中
你在读什么呢
What are you reading?
板球比赛而已
Just the cricket.
我们是个摇滚乐队
We're a rock and roll band.
我们不搞迪斯科
We don't do disco.
-这不是迪斯科  -那是什么
- It's not disco. - Then what is it?
这是皇后乐队
It's Queen.
太抱歉了  亲爱的们
So sorry, my darlings!
时间全忘了
Lost all track!
你竟然和我们招呼都不打就把里德炒了
You fired Reid without consulting us!
你不能为整个乐队做决定
You don't make decisions for the band.
真是太抱歉了  亲爱的
Well, I'm terribly sorry, dear.
事情已经定了
It's done.
再说了
Besides...
迈阿密会做我们的经纪人
Miami will manage us.
对吧  亲爱的
Won't you, darling?
我会考虑一下的
I'll think about it.
不  你又嗑嗨了吗
No. Are you high again?
真厉害  大侦探
Well done, Columbo.
你得悠着点  弗雷
You need to slow down, Fred.
-别扫兴  我人不是在这儿了  -你魂在吗
- Oh, don't be such a bore. I'm here, aren't I? - Are you?
我不管你是不是一副臭脸
I don't care if you're shit-faced.
只要能唱歌就行
As long as you can sing.
不  约翰  我不想做这首
No, John, I don't wanna play it.
那我就一定要做这首
Then I'm all for it.
你几个意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我唱颂歌唱的都烦了
I'm tired of the bloody anthems.
我想要夜店里的那种活力
I want the energy in the clubs.
那些肉体
The bodies.
-我想要人们动起来  -你是说迪斯科
- I want to make people move. - You mean disco?
为什么不呢
Why not?
你介意滚开吗  我们这是乐队内部讨论
Do you mind pissing off? This is a band discussion.
鼓循环  电子合成器
Drum loops? Synthesizers?
-你说是就是吧  -这不是我们的风格
- If you say so. - It's not us!
-我们  -这不是皇后乐队
- Us? - It's not Queen!
皇后乐队由我说了算
Queen is whatever I say it is!
那你自个儿打鼓去吧
You can play your own bloody drums, then.
弗雷
Fred.
行啊  我倒要看看你是个多牛逼的拳手
Okay, let's see how good a boxer you really are!
罗杰  别冲动  别冲动
Roger, take it easy! Take it easy!
别冲动
Take it easy.
你够了  拳王阿里
All right, Muhammad Ali.
那个
That's...
那个乐节确实还挺不错的
That's quite a cool riff, actually.
是你谱的
You wrote that?
真不赖
That's really good.
没错  要是你们
Yes, it will be...
全都给我闭嘴开始表演  那才是真不错
if you all can just shut up and play.
-是他起的头  -闭嘴吧你
- He started it. - Oh, shut up!
♪ 史蒂夫无精打采的走在街上 ♪
♪ Steve walks warily down the street ♪
♪ 帽沿拉得很低很低 ♪
♪ With the brim pulled way down low ♪
♪ 街道很静  唯有他的脚步声清晰 ♪
♪ Ain't no sound but the sound of his feet ♪
♪ 机枪早已上了膛 ♪
♪ Machine guns ready to go ♪
♪ 你准备好了吗 ♪
♪ Are you ready ♪
♪ 你为此准备好了吗 ♪
♪ Are you ready for this? ♪
♪ 你是不是已经蠢蠢欲动 ♪
♪ Are you hanging on the edge of your seat? ♪
♪ 门外子弹呼啸 ♪
♪ Out of the doorway the bullets rip ♪
这活我干
Okay, I'll do it.
♪ 随着节拍划破长空 ♪
♪ To the sound of the beat ♪
这活  我干
I'll do it.
你即兴发挥就好  想怎样就怎样
Oh, just improvise. Just give it whatever you want.
这没问题
I can do that.
♪ 一起来 ♪
♪ Let's go! ♪
♪ 史蒂夫无精打采的走在街上 ♪
♪ Steve walks warily down the street ♪
♪ 帽沿拉得很低很低 ♪
♪ With the brim pulled way down low ♪
♪ 街道很静  唯有他的脚步声清晰 ♪
♪ Ain't no sound but the sound of his feet ♪
♪ 机枪早已上了膛 ♪
♪ Machine guns ready to go ♪
♪ 你准备好了吗  你为此准备好了吗 ♪
♪ Are you ready, hey, are you ready for this? ♪
♪ 你是不是已经蠢蠢欲动 ♪
♪ Are you hanging on the edge of your seat? ♪
♪ 门外子弹呼啸 ♪
♪ Out of the doorway the bullets rip ♪
♪ 随着节拍划破长空 ♪
♪ To the sound of the beat, yeah ♪
♪ 又有一个人倒下 ♪
♪ Another one bites the dust ♪
♪ 一个又一个倒下 ♪
♪ And another one gone and another one gone ♪
♪ 又有一个人倒下 ♪
♪ Another one bites the dust ♪
这主意不错
That's a good idea.
♪ 我也会抓到你 ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you, too ♪
♪ 又有一个人倒下 ♪
♪ Another one bites the dust ♪
♪ 你说我接下来要怎么生活 ♪
♪ How do you think I'm gonna get along ♪
♪ 现在你已不在 ♪
♪ Without you when you're gone? ♪
♪ 你不过是贪图我的风光 ♪
♪ You took me for everything that I had ♪
♪ 末了又将我抛弃 ♪
♪ And kicked me out on my own ♪
♪ 现在你开心了  满意了吧 ♪
♪ Are you happy, are you satisfied? ♪
♪ 这样的炙热你还能忍耐多久 ♪
♪ How long can you stand the heat? ♪
♪ 门外子弹呼啸 ♪
♪ Out of the doorway the bullets rip ♪
♪ 随着节拍划破长空 ♪
♪ To the sound of the beat, yeah ♪
弗雷迪
Freddie!
-弗雷迪  -弗雷迪  作为皇后乐队的队长
- Freddie! - Freddie, as the leader of Queen...
作为皇后乐队的队长
As the leader of Queen...
你是否觉得是自己引领了乐队的成功
do you feel responsible for the success of the band?
伦敦      年
我不是皇后乐队队长  我只是主唱
I'm not the leader of Queen, I'm only the lead singer.
弗雷迪  我有个问题要问弗雷迪
Freddie! A question for Freddie.
你是否怀疑过自己的才能
Do you ever doubt your talent?
没有  这是个愚蠢的问题
No, that's a stupid question.
-别冲动  弗雷  -下一个问题
- Take it easy, Fred. - What's next?
弗雷迪  你的牙齿
Freddie, uh, your teeth!
你为什么不去整牙
Why don't you get your teeth fixed?
我生活在英国  我想和大家保持一致
I live in Britain. I don't want to stand out.
-下一个  -你怎么不整整自己的礼节
- Next... - Why don't you have your manners fixed?
这对任何人来说都是个混账问题
That's an asshole question to ask anybody.
的确是个混账问题
That's an asshole question.
在你的歌曲《生活是真实的》中
In your song Life Is Real,
"爱情宛若轮盘赌"
what do you mean by the line...
这句话是什么意思
"Love is a roulette wheel"?
你是在暗示拥有的伴侣越多
Are you implying that the more partners you have...
就越有可能...
the more chances you have of...
染上一些东西
contracting something?
什么
What?
我不知道  我还没搞懂爱情
I don't know, I haven't figured out love yet.
但这句话别有深意  弗雷迪
But it implies something else, Freddie.
也许罗更适合来回答这个问题
That might be a better question for Rog.
说话小心点
Watch it.
弗雷迪  关于你的私生活
Freddie, concerning your private life...
小报上有很多你的照片
there's lots of pictures of you in the tabloids...
看上去醉醺醺或是病怏怏
looking drunk or ill.
到底是怎么回事  你是病了还是酗酒
Which one is it, ill or drunk?
我上周感冒了  如果有人关心的话
I had a cold last week, if anyone cares.
尽管我们非常乐意回答关于感冒的问题
As much as we'd love to answer questions about colds...
我更想谈谈专辑
I'd like to speak about the album.
各位有音乐方面的问题吗
If anyone's got any questions about the music?
弗雷迪  弗雷迪  弗雷迪
Freddie! Freddie! Freddie!
弗雷迪  弗雷迪  你的父母
Freddie! Freddie, your parents...
是保守的琐罗亚斯德教教徒
they're conservative Zoroastrians.
我想知道  他们是怎么看待你的公众形象的
I wonder, what do they make of your public persona?
-这和音乐  -我父母死于火灾
- Is that music... - My parents died in a fiery wreck.
我恰好了解到这并非事实  不是吗
I happen to know that's not true, is it?
我只是想知道他们是否以你为傲
I just wanted to know whether they were proud of you.
你的父母以你为傲吗
Are your parents proud of you?
你出落成他们所期望的模样了吗
Is this what they hoped for?
我希望他们是以我为傲的
I hope that they are.
我可不敢苟同
I surely don't think so.
有人想聊聊专辑吗
Anyone wanna talk about the album?
弗雷迪  弗雷迪  弗雷迪
Freddie! Freddie! Freddie!
能否请你回答一下我的问题
Could you answer my questions please?
希望是个好问题
This better be good.
都闭嘴
Shut up!
弗雷迪  你能否和我们谈谈
Freddie, could you tell us about the rumors
有关你性向的传言呢
concerning your sexuality?
不如谈谈有关你缺乏性生活的传言
What about the rumors concerning your lack of sexuality?
我只是个音乐娼妓  亲爱的
I'm just a musical prostitute, my dear.
你能回答问题吗
Can you answer the question?
你叫什么名字  亲爱的
What's your name, dear?
雪莉·斯特恩
Shelley Stern.
-雪莉  -我在
- Shelley. - Yes.
你两腿之间那玩意儿咬人吗
That thing between your legs, does it bite?
请你回答问题
Could you answer the question, please?
我们只是出于礼节坐这儿的
We're here as a courtesy.
台上可坐着四个人
You know, there's four of us up here.
你在怕什么  弗雷迪
What are you afraid of, Freddie?
你想听什么
What do you want?
真相是什么
What is the truth?
你就不能说一次实话吗
Can you be honest for once?
你为什么要在父母的事情上说谎  弗雷迪
Why are you lying about your parents, Freddie?
我没有撒谎  我只是...
I'm not lying about anything. I just, I'm...
你的粉丝理应了解真相  弗雷迪
Your fans deserve to know the truth, Freddie.
请你回答问题
Can you answer the question, please?
这不关你的事
It's my business.This is my business.
-不  你是公众人物  -你在怕什么  弗雷迪
- No, you're a public figure. -What are you afraid of, Freddie?
-你的父母  -能否告诉我们
- Your parents? - Can you tell us
-关于  -你的性向
- about... - Your sexuality?
什么  为什么  为什么
What? Why, why...
-你就不能诚实一点吗  -染上什么东西
- Can you just be honest? - Contracting something.
你的粉丝理应了解真相
Your fans deserve to know the truth.
我们的读者想知道
Our readers want to know.
你的读者想知道什么
What do your readers want to know?
他们想知道什么
They want to know what?
I Want To Break Free
♪ 生活仍要继续 ♪
♪ But life still goes on ♪
♪ 我无法忍受生活里没有 ♪
♪ I can't get used to living without ♪
♪ 生活里没有 ♪
♪ Living without ♪
♪ 生活里没有你 ♪
♪ Living without you by my side ♪
♪ 我不愿孤身一人 ♪
♪ I don't want to live alone ♪
♪ 天知道 ♪
♪ God knows ♪
♪ 生活却必须要孤孤单单继续 ♪
♪ Got to make it on my own ♪
♪ 宝贝  你难道看不出来 ♪
♪ So, baby, can't you see? ♪
♪ 我必须挣脱你 ♪
♪ I've got to break free ♪
棒  我可以坐起来了吗
Brilliant! Can I get up now?
这是什么情况
What is happening?
不  不可以
No, you can't.
-人家也要坐进来  -从我身上滚下去
- I wanna be in it. - Get off me!
吉姆·赫顿
弗雷迪  你在里面吗
Freddie, you in there?
弗雷迪
Freddie?
他们到了
They're here.
我们不能再拖了
We can't put this off any longer.
弗雷迪
Freddie?
MTV把我们的视频禁了
MTV banned our video.
说什么毒害美国的年轻一代
The youth of America.
MTV还是我们捧红的
We helped give birth to MTV.
那可是美国
It's America.
他们表面正人君子  背地里却净是下流勾当
They're Puritans in public, perverts in private.
我再也不去美国巡演了
I'm never touring in the U.S. again.
而且我还成了那个背黑锅的
And I'm the one being blamed for it.
不是你  亲爱的
Not you, dear...
变装明明是你的主意
whose idea, I believe, it was to dress up in drag.
也不是你
And not you.
甚至不是你  这破歌是你写的
Not even you, who wrote the bloody thing.
不是你们
No.
是那个穿异装的疯子弗雷迪
Crazy, cross-dressing Freddie.
是变态弗雷迪  基佬弗雷迪
Freddie the freak. Freddie the fag.
我受够了巡演  难道你们没有吗
I'm tired of touring. Aren't you?
专辑  巡演  专辑  巡演
Album, tour, album, tour.
我想做一些不一样的事
I want to do something different.
我们是个乐队  乐队就该如此
We're a band. That's what bands do.
-专辑  巡演  专辑  巡演  -我要休息一阵
- Album, tour, album, tour. - Well, I need a break.
我受够了
I'm sick of it.
你想说什么  弗雷迪
What are you saying, Freddie?
我和哥伦比亚唱片公司签了合同
I've signed a deal with CBS Records.
-你什么  -和我们招呼都不打一声吗
- You've done what? - Without telling us?
什么合同
What kind of deal?
听着  我不是说再也不录歌或不巡演了
Look, I'm not saying we won't record or ever tour again.
皇后乐队会一直走下去
Queen will go on.
但我要做些不一样的事
But I need to do something different.
明白我的意思吗  我需要成长
Do you know what I mean? I need to grow.
那首歌是什么来着  歌词是"高飞"
What's the song? "Fly away"?
此处指的是由贝斯手约翰·迪肯谱曲作词的
"Spread Your Wings"
"展开双翅  远走高飞"
"Spread my wings and fly away."
一张个人专辑
A solo album?
两张  其实
Two, actually.
-连发  -你再说一句
- Back to back. - Another word out of you...
我就把你从窗子里扔出去
and I'll throw you out the bloody window.
那得是好几年  弗雷迪
But that's years, Freddie.
-那得花上好几年  -能不能有点信心
-  I mean... that'll take years. - Ye of little faith.
简直不敢相信
I don't believe this.
多少钱
How much?
他们给了你多少
What did they pay you?
我想知道他们给了你多少钱
I wanna know how much they paid you...
四百万美元
$4 million!
比皇后乐队任何一次的薪酬都高
That's more than any Queen deal.
例行公事只会扼杀我们
Look, the routine is killing us.
你们一定也想从所有那些争执中解放出来
I mean, you must all want a break from all the arguments.
谁的歌上专辑
I mean, whose song gets on the album...
谁的歌是单曲
whose song's the single...
谁写了什么
who wrote what...
谁拿的版税多
who gets a bigger slice of the royalties...
谁的歌在唱片B面  所有这些
what's on the B-side, all of it.
你们一定也需要放个假
You must need a break.
弗雷迪  我们是一家人
Freddie, we're a family.
不  我们不是
No, we're not!
我们才不是一家人
We're not a family!
你们都有家庭  孩子  妻子
You've got families, children, wives.
我有什么
What have I got?
你有了四百万美金  或许你能给自己买个家
You've got $4 million. Perhaps you can buy yourself a family.
我再也不会拿自己的未来做让步
I won't compromise my vision any longer.
让步
Compromise?
你开什么玩笑
Are you joking?
当初你在希思罗工作时
You were working at Heathrow
是我们给了你一个机会
before we gave you a chance.
要是没了我
And without me...
你不过是个小牙医
you'd be a dentist...
周末在冠与锚酒吧给12/8拍的蓝调敲鼓伴奏
drumming 12/8-time blues at the weekend at the Crown and Anchor.
而你
And you.
你则会成为布莱恩·梅博士
Well, you would be Dr. Brian May...
写了一篇引人入胜的关于宇宙的论文
author of a fascinating dissertation on the cosmos...
却无人问津
that no one ever reads.
至于迪迪你
And Deacy...
我是绞尽脑汁
for the life of me...
也想不出来你该干哪行
nothing comes to mind.
我是学电气工程的
I studied electrical engineering.
达到你的标准了吗
Does that meet your standard?
棒极了
Perfect.
你刚一把毁了皇后乐队
You just killed Queen.
某天给她一个吻  说不定还能活过来
Oh, give it a kiss one day. She might wake up.
你需要我们  弗雷迪
You need us, Freddie.
远胜于你意识到的
More than you know.
我不需要任何人
I don't need anyone.
慕尼黑     年
喂
Hello?
保罗  我能和弗雷迪说两句吗
Paul. Can I speak to Freddie?
不行啊玛丽  他现在没空
Oh, Mary. No, he can't talk right now.
他现在是没日没夜地工作
He's working day and night, constantly.
你一定要告诉他我打来过
Will you make sure to tell him that I called?
别担心  他被照顾得好着呢
Don't worry, he's in safe hands.
我一定会告诉他你打来了的
I will certainly tell him you called.
拜拜
Cheers.
弗雷迪  这真的很棒
Freddie, it's really great.
这简直是狗屎
It's shit!
别管它
Just leave it.
没错  稍等一下
Yeah, hang on one second.
高音再加一点
Give it more treble.
他人在哪  在那儿吗  我要和他说两句
Where is he? Is he there? I wanna speak to him.
他正在拼着老命工作
He is working himself to the bone.
劝他休息我是劝的口干舌燥
I'm blue in the face trying to get him to take a break.
保罗  你听我说
Paul, listen to me.
这是一次慈善演出
It's one performance for a good cause.
是为埃塞俄比亚大饥荒举行的电视直播演唱会
It's a televised concert for the famine in Ethiopia.
届时费城和伦敦同时举行演出
They're gonna have simultaneous performances in Philadelphia and London.
将会有十亿人收看
There's gonna be a billion people watching.
皇后乐队应当参加
Queen should be part of it.
他真的一直都很专注
He's just been really focused.
不过我一定会传达你的意思
But I'll be sure to pass it on.
你会才怪
Sure you will.
你好啊
Hi.
你好啊  进来吧  进来
Hi. Come in, come in.
你怎么这么大老远的跑来
Why did you come all this way?
我只是太久没有你的信儿了
I just haven't heard from you in so long,
我打了一个又一个电话  然后
and I phoned and phoned, and then...
昨天晚上我做了个噩梦
last night I just had this terrible dream
梦见你出了大事
that something bad had happened.
不不  我只是在工作罢了
No, no. I've been working, that's all.
弗雷迪  你过分地燃烧自己了
Freddie, you're burning the candle at both ends.
但发出的光芒是多么神圣啊
Yes, but the glow is so divine.
做人有些时候就需要一些麻醉
Being human is a condition that requires a little anesthesia.
-我想你了  -我也想你
- I miss you. - I miss you.
我好想好想你
I miss you so much.
但我还得完成第二张专辑
Listen, but I have to finish the second album.
我需要你
I need you.
留下吧  留下来陪我
Stay. Stay here with me.
就你和我
Just you and me.
我需要此生挚爱的陪伴
I need the love of my life.
弗雷迪
Freddie...
那皇后乐队呢
What about Queen?
吉姆告诉我他一直想和你谈谈"拯救生命"的事
Jim told me he's been trying to contact you about Live Aid...
但你不接他电话
and you won't take his calls.
什么是"拯救生命"
What is Live Aid?
你没听说吗
You haven't heard?
弗雷迪  这是有史以来
Freddie, it's the biggest concert
最大型的演唱会  以后也难被超越
there's ever been or ever will be.
是为了非洲的饥荒
It's for the famine in Africa.
可能保罗觉得这不是个好主意
Well, perhaps Paul thought it wasn't a good idea.
会干扰我的工作
A distraction from my work.
把专辑完成才是最重要的事
That's what's important, that I finish this album.
留下来陪我  亲爱的  我就什么都好了
Stay with me, darling, and I'll be all right.
弗雷迪  我不能留下
Freddie, I can't stay with you.
你当然可以  我需要你  玛丽
Of course you can. I need you, Mary.
弗雷迪  我怀孕了
Freddie, I'm pregnant.
你怎么能够
How could you?
我怎么能够
How could I?
弗雷迪  这轮不到你指手画脚
Freddie, this has nothing to do with you.
来吧  进屋来
Come on. Let's get in.
我买了点小零食
I bought some nibbles.
弗雷迪
Freddie.
抱歉来晚了
Sorry we're late.
玛丽
Mary.
真是意外之喜
What a pleasant surprise.
汉斯  大家伙  都进来吧
Hans. Everyone, come in.
米兰  招待好客人们
Milan, make our guests comfortable.
你来过夜怎么不提前告诉我
I wish I knew you were coming to stay.
否则我非得把这地方刷的锃亮不可
I'd have scrubbed the place.
其实  我要走了
Actually, I'm not staying.
等等  玛丽  等等  别走
Wait. Mary, wait. Don't go.
你告诉我你做了个梦
You told me you had a dream.
是什么梦
What was it?
我想和你说话  但...
I was trying to talk to you, but...
感觉却像是和我爸爸说话一样
it was like talking to my father.
你要告诉我些什么
You needed to tell me something...
但你却说不出来
but you couldn't say it.
因为你失了声
Because you had no voice.
弗雷迪  来和我们的新客人打声招呼
Freddie, come and say hello to our new guests.
他们迫不及待想见你了
They're dying to meet you.
他马上就来
He'll be one second.
玛丽
Mary!
我为你高兴  玛丽
I'm happy for you, Mary.
我真的高兴
Truly, I am.
只是...
It's just...
我好害怕
I'm frightened.
弗雷迪  你不必怕
Freddie, you don't need to be.
因为不管怎样  都有人爱你
Because no matter what, you are loved.
我  布莱恩  迪迪  罗杰
By me, by Brian, Deacy, Roger...
你的家人
your family.
这就够了
It's enough.
那些人
And these people...
他们才不在乎你
they don't care about you.
保罗不在乎你
Paul doesn't care about you.
你不属于这里  弗雷迪
You don't belong here, Freddie.
回家吧
Come home.
家
Home.
弗雷迪
Freddie!
你做什么呢  别冻病了
What are you doing? You'll catch your death.
你为什么没告诉我"拯救生命"演唱会的事
Why didn't you tell me about Live Aid?
那个非洲慈善演出吗
The Africa charity gig?
那绝对会出丑的
It'll be an embarrassment.
我可不想浪费你的时间
I didn't wanna waste your time.
你本该告诉我的
You should have told me.
我当然告诉过你
Of course I did.
是你忘了
You forgot.
你忘性大
You're always forgetting things.
赶紧进来喝一杯吧
Come in now and have a drink.
你被炒了
You're out.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我希望你从我的生命中滚蛋
I want you out of my life.
就因为你只剩我了
'Cause I'm the only one left,
所以把一切都怪罪在我头上吗
you're blaming me for everything?
我怪我自己
I blame myself.
我就这么被炒了
So I'm out?
这么轻巧吗
Just like that?
在我们一起经历了那一切之后
After everything we've been through?
你想想我手里的那些照片
Just think of the photos I have.
我了解真正的你  弗雷迪·默丘里
I know who you are, Freddie Mercury.
你知道人什么时候会察觉自己已经腐烂了吗
You know when you know you've gone rotten?
烂透了那种
Really rotten?
果蝇
Fruit flies.
肮脏的小果蝇
Dirty little fruit flies.
来残渣上大快朵颐
Coming to feast on what's left.
但如今已经不剩什么供你享用了
Well, there isn't much left for you to feast on anymore.
滚吧
So, fly off.
随便你拿那些照片和故事怎么样
Do what you like with your photographs and your stories.
但答应我一件事
But promise me one thing.
永远都不要再让我看见你的脸
That I never see your face again.
永远
Ever.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean it.
Under Pressure
♪ Pressure pushing down on me ♪
对不起  弗雷迪  回来
I'm sorry! Freddie, come back!
♪ Pressing down on you no man ask for ♪
我会改的
I'll make it better.
♪ Under pressure that brings a building down ♪
♪ Splits a family in two ♪
♪ Puts people on streets ♪
但是  皮特  也许你说得对
But, Peter, you might be right.
我甚至都没有因为
I'm not even hurt
他身为我的朋友却赶我走而受伤
by the fact that he's let me go as a friend.
但你帮人只能帮到那个地步了
But you can only be there so much for a person.
那么  普兰特先生...
And so, Mr. Prenter...
所有关于弗雷迪·默丘里和他的情人们的故事
all these stories about Freddie Mercury and his lovers...
真的太多了
that there were so many.
嗯
Yeah?
-它们是真的吗  -是的
- Is it really true? - Yes, it is.
他的情人不计其数
His lovers were countless.
真的是非常多
Genuinely countless.
所有那些疯狂的  充斥着毒品的派对...
All these wild, drug-fueled parties...
他每晚都从中寻找新的情人...
where he'd find another lover every night...
这是他摆脱不了的习惯
and a routine he couldn't get out of.
所以说你真的了解面具后的他
So, you really did see behind the mask?
我在弗雷迪创作《波西米亚狂想曲》的时候就认识他了
I knew Freddie when he did Bohemian Rhapsody.
而如今的弗雷迪...
And the Freddie we have now...
他对音乐不再有同样的激情了
he doesn't have the same passion about music.
喂
Hello?
迈阿密
Miami?
弗雷迪
Freddie?
你还好吗
How are you?
有这么一个非洲演唱会...
There was this Africa concert...
想要皇后乐队参演
that wants Queen to play.
现在还来得及...
Is that still...
你是指"拯救生命"演唱会吗
You mean Live Aid?
他们已经公布了所有参演乐队了  弗雷迪
They've announced all the bands, Freddie.
已经太迟了
It's too late.
我需要...
I need...
我需要重新和母舰取得联系
I need to reconnect with the mothership.
弗雷迪  他们不想和你扯上任何关系
Freddie, they don't want anything to do with you.
他们一直很生气
They're still very upset.
也许如果由你提出来的话...
Maybe if you ask them...
他们会愿意见我
they would meet me.
告诉他们我想聊聊
Tell them I want to talk.
只是聊聊
Just talk.
我们是家人
We're family.
家人...
You know, family...
会争吵...
have fights...
总是如此
all the time.
我可以打个电话
I can call.
谢谢你...
Thank you...
吉姆
Jim.
作为他的朋友  一个...
As this friend, somebody who...
八成比其他任何人都更了解弗雷迪·默丘里的人...
probably knows Freddie Mercury better than anybody else...
你对他这个人的内心有什么样的评价
how would you describe him inside as a person?
于我而言  弗雷迪永远都会是...
For me, Freddie will always be...
一个惶恐的巴基斯坦小男孩...
this frightened little Pakkie boy...
对孤独充满恐惧
who's afraid to be alone.
我希望他能看见这个
I hope he sees this
然后醒悟过来失去你他到底损失了什么
and realizes what he has lost in you.
我也希望如此
I hope he does, too.
一位亲密且重要的朋友
A close and important friend.
他们在哪
Where are they?
他们迟到了
They're late.
你们好呀
Hi, guys.
吉姆
Jim.
有人想要茶水  咖啡...
If anybody wants any tea, coffee...
或者刀子的话...
bladed weapons...
直接...
just...
说一声就好
just ask.
那么...
So...
谁想第一个说
who wants to go first?
我先说
I'll start.
我一直很讨人厌
I've been hideous.
我知道
I know that, and...
我活该承受你们的怒火
I deserve your fury.
我自大...
I've been conceited...
自私
selfish.
基本上就是个王八蛋
Well, an asshole, basically.
这开头够劲
Strong beginning.
听着  我很乐意把衣服脱了...
Look, I'm happy to strip off my shirt...
在你们面前自鞭谢罪
and flagellate myself before you.
但是  我想问你们一个简单的问题
Or rather, I could ask you a simple question.
我挺赞同自鞭谢罪的
I'm good with the flagellation.
我要怎么做你们所有人才能原谅我
What's it gonna take for you all to forgive me?
这就是你的目的吗  弗雷迪
Is that what you want, Freddie?
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
-行了吗  我们现在能走了吗  -不
- Is that it? Can we go now? - No.
我去了慕尼黑
I went to Munich.
雇了一帮人
I hired a bunch of guys.
我清楚地告诉了他们我需要他们做什么...
I told them exactly what I wanted them to do...
但问题在于...
and the problem was...
他们照做了
they did it.
没有罗杰的质疑
No pushback from Roger.
没有你的重写
None of your rewrites.
没有他那搞笑的表情
None of his funny looks.
我需要你们
I need you.
你们也需要我
And you need me.
承认吧
Let's face it.
作为四个老皇后我们还不赖
We're not bad for four aging queens.
所以...说吧
So, um, go ahead.
说出你们的条件
Name your terms.
能给我们点时间吗  麻烦了  弗雷
Could you give us a moment, please, Fred?
为什么要让他出去
Why'd you do that?
我就想这么做
I just felt like it.
他们会答应的  他们只是需要点时间
They'll be all right. They just need a bit of time.
如果我没时间了呢
What if I don't have time?
这话什么意思  弗雷
What do you mean, Fred?
你现在可以进来了  如果你愿意的话
You can come back in now, if you'd like.
我们决定...
We decided...
我们怎么决定的来着
What did we decide?
从现在开始...
From now on...
每一首歌  不管是谁写的  作曲  填词...
every song, no matter who wrote it, music, lyrics...
都署名皇后乐队
it's by Queen.
不署我们个人  只用皇后乐队
Not one of us, just Queen.
所有的收入  功劳
All the money, all the credits,
都平均分成四份
split four ways evenly.
没问题
Done.
我们对你身边的人很有意见
We have a problem with the people around you.
保罗已经走了  我炒了他
Paul is out. I fired him.
-以什么原因  -恶行
- On what pretext? - Villainy.
还有什么
What else?
鲍勃·吉尔道夫
Bob Geldof.
我打电话说服了他把你们插进
I called to convince him to squeeze you guys
"拯救生命"演唱会的阵容...
into the lineup for the Live Aid concert...
但他现在就要答复
but he wants an answer now.
你们得做出决定
You have to make a decision.
所有票都卖出去了
Every ticket's already sold.
温布利球场有十万人
100,000 people at Wembley...
费城肯尼迪体育馆有十万人
100,000 people at JFK Stadium in Philadelphia...
全球150个国家的电视观众
a global TV audience around the world of 150 countries...
13个卫星
13 satellites.
奥运会都只有3个
The Olympics only had three.
我们好几年没有合作过了
We haven't played together in years.
重聚后的第一次就在上百万人前表演
It's kinda suicide to play again for the first time
简直是自杀
in front of millions.
准确地说是超过十亿五千万人
Try over 1.5 billion.
"这四个老古董是谁"
"Who are these four dinosaurs?"
"麦当娜在哪"
"Where's Madonna?"
表演时长20分钟  每队人马都一样
It's a 20-minute set. Everyone gets the same.
贾格尔
Jagger,
鲍威
Bowie...
艾尔顿
Elton...
麦卡特尼
McCartney,
谁人乐队
The Who...
齐伯林飞艇乐队
Led Zeppelin...
菲尔·科林斯
Phil Collins,
REO快速马车乐队
REO Speedwagon...
鲍勃·迪伦
Bob Dylan.
都是些大牌
Certainly good company.
所有有头有脸的人物都要参加这次演唱会
Anybody who is anybody is doing this concert.
听着
Look.
我只知道...
All I know...
如果我们在这场演唱会的第二天醒来
is that if we wake up the day after this concert...
并且没有参演...
and we didn't do our part...
我们会一直后悔到到死的那天的
we're going to regret it till the day we die.
求你们了
Please.
每一天  在旧金山
Every day, in San Francisco,
都会有两个男人得知那个悲惨的消息
two more men hear the grim news...
"你得了艾滋  没得治"
"You have AIDS, there's no cure."
自从法国和美国的医生
Since doctors in France and America
在1983年分离出了这种病毒
isolated the virus in 1983...
相关研究就一直在以高速进行着
research has proceeded at a frantic pace.
病毒用来破坏身体免疫系统的方式
The method used by the virus to destroy the body's immune system...
Who Wants To Live Forever
♪ There's no time for us ♪
已经被发现了
has been discovered...
但治疗方法的出现似乎依旧离我们有数年之遥
but a cure still seems many years away.
新的血液测试是一项重大的突破
A major breakthrough has been a new blood test...
♪ There's no place for us ♪
该测试能保证在未来
that should ensure that in future...
没有人会因为输血而感染艾滋病
nobody contracts AIDS from a blood transfusion.
但该测试刚刚才获准使用
But it's only just been approved for use.
♪ What is this thing that builds our dreams ♪
♪ Yet slips away from us? ♪
♪ Who wants to live forever? ♪
♪ There's no chance for us ♪
♪ It's all decided for us ♪
♪ This world has only one ♪
♪ Sweet moment set aside for us ♪
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
你这个阶段确实可以去治疗
The way we go from here is that treatments are available.
但都不是很有效  弗雷迪
They're not particularly effective, Freddie.
♪ 明知我们的声音无法被听见 ♪
♪ Convinced our voices can't be heard ♪
♪ 但只想呐喊得大声大声更大声 ♪
♪ We just want to scream it louder and louder ♪
♪ 我们到底在为什么而战 ♪
♪ What the hell are we fighting for? ♪
♪ 不如就此投降  这样就不会受伤 ♪
♪ Just surrender and it won't hurt at all ♪
好吧
Yep.
-就到这里吧  怎样  -好好
- Let's call it. Yeah? - Yeah, yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
我听上去像屎一样
I sound like shit.
你们都很好  听起来很棒
You all are lovely, sound good.
有一阵子了
Been a while.
我的嗓子感觉像是公鸭嗓
My throat feels like a vulture's crotch.
我们还有一周呢
We still got a week.
我们会成功的
We'll get there.
是啊  我们状态不错  弗雷
Yeah, we're in a good place, Fred.
你只是需要休息一下  仅此而已
You just need a bit of rest, that's all.
是啊
Yeah.
去喝一杯吗  罗
Get a drink, Rog?
好啊  正好路上有一家不错的小酒馆
Yeah, there's a nice little pub down the road, actually.
-我能一起去吗  -不  当然不行
- Can I come? - No, of course not.
-我们可是会员...  -邀请制的
- We're just an exclusive... - Invite-only.
可不是嘛  是你们的风格
Yeah, that's kind of you.
在你们离开之前...
Before you leave...
我能占用一点时间吗
Could I have a second?
可以啊  怎么了
Yeah. What's up?
我得了
I've got it.
得了什么
Got what?
艾滋
AIDS.
我想让你们从我这里得到消息
I wanted you to hear it from me.
弗雷  我很遗憾
Fred, I'm so sorry.
布莱恩  停
Brian, stop.
别
Don't.
目前...
For right now...
这事你知我知  好吗  只有我们
it's between us. All right? Just us.
所以拜托了...
So, please...
如果你们中的任何一个人
if any of you...
大惊小怪  哭丧着脸  或者最糟的
fuss about it or frown about it, or, worst of all...
用你们的同情来烦我...
if you bore me with your sympathy...
那就是浪费时间
that's just seconds wasted.
浪费可以用来做音乐的时间
Seconds that could be used making music...
而我剩下的时间只想用来做音乐
which is all I want to do with the time I have left.
我没有时间去做他们的受害者
I don't have time to be their victim...
他们的艾滋海报模特  他们的警世例子
their AIDS poster boy, their cautionary tale.
不  我是谁由我做主
No, I decide who I am.
我要成为我生来就要成为的人
I'm going to be what I was born to be.
一个表演者
A performer...
一个能给人们他们想要的东西的人
who gives the people what they want.
能给他们天堂般的体验
Touch of the heavens.
牛逼的弗雷迪·默丘里
Freddie fucking Mercury.
你是个传奇  弗雷
You're a legend, Fred.
你说得太他妈对了  我就是
You're bloody right I am.
我们都是传奇
We're all legends.
但没错  我就是个传奇
But you're right, I am a legend.
你们给我个机会
Now, you give me a chance
让我调理好我磨人的小声带
to get my bitchy little vocal cords in order...
我们会把那个体育馆的天花板捅穿的
and we'll go and punch a hole through the roof of that stadium.
实际上  温布利没有天花板
Actually, Wembley doesn't have a roof.
-好吧  -确实  他说得对  的确没有
- All right. - No, he's right. It doesn't.
那我们就把天空捅穿
Then we'll punch a hole in the sky.
尽管你们哭哭啼啼的像三个小姑娘似的
Now, even though you're crying like three little girls...
我依旧爱你们
I still love you.
-好了  够了  -好吧
- All right, enough of this. - All right.
-喝酒去  -好
- Drink? - Yes!
或者抽一点
Or ten?
年  "拯救生命"演唱会当日
你看什么看
What are you looking at?
你们觉得自己能唱得比我好吗
You think you could do better?
人人都是个评论家
Everyone's a critic.
现在是伦敦时间正午12点
It's 12:00 noon in London.
费城时间早上7点
7:00 a.m. in Philadelphia.
全世界瞩目的"拯救生命"演唱会现在开启
And around the world, it's time for Live Aid.
如果你们有信用卡
If you have credit cards...
可以打电话捐款
you can phone up with the number you want to give.
你还可以使用现金担保  这也是很重要的
But you can also pledge cash, and it's very important.
现在捐款数额还不够多
There is not enough money coming in...
所有那些人都不是在为了自己的福祉演奏
and all these people are not playing for the good of their health.
他们是在为全人类的福祉演奏
They're playing for the good of other people's health.
所以赶紧把你们的钱掏出来
So get your money out now!
打电话过来  给我们捐钱
And phone up and give us the money.
你们腰缠万贯  或者就算你们身无分文
You've got plenty of it, or if you got none of it...
也要为那些快要饿死的人出一份力
get it to people who are dying of starvation.
我们想在国内募捐一百万英镑
We want to get a million pounds out of this country.
电话捐款  今晚10点前
On the telephone, before 10:00 tonight.
你到底知不知道...
Do you have any idea...
全伦敦有多少个吉姆·赫顿
how many Jim Huttons there are in London?
我不想让你过于轻而易举了
Well, I didn't want to make it too easy for you.
你最近怎么样啊  弗雷迪
How have you been, Freddie?
我有点迷茫  说实话
I've been a bit lost, to be honest.
你之前说得对
You were right.
我挺需要个朋友的
I could do with a friend.
愿意和我一起喝个茶吗
Would you like to have tea with me?
喝茶
Tea?
那么  吉姆  你是怎么认识弗雷迪的
So, Jim, how do you know Freddie?
你俩是同事吗
Do you work together?
吉姆是我的朋友
Jim's my friend.
有朋友是件好事
Wonderful to have friends.
点心  洁自己做的
Mithai. Jer made it herself.
谢谢
Thank you.
-弗雷迪  -你最喜欢的  弗雷迪
- Freddie? - Your favorite, Freddie.
我们得走了  妈
We have to go, Mum.
你才刚到呢  儿子
But you just got here, beta.
"走"是什么意思
What do you mean, "go"?
我们得去温布利
We've gotta get to Wembley.
你们敢信吗
Would you believe it?
吉姆居然从来没去过摇滚演唱会
Jim's never been to a rock concert.
真的
That's true.
皇后乐队要去"拯救生命"演唱会表演
Queen are playing at Live Aid.
我们都在为非洲的饥荒儿童尽一份力
We're all doing our bit for the starving children in Africa...
所有人都是义务表演
and nobody's taking any money.
睿智  善语  良行
Good thoughts, good words, good deeds.
和您教我的一样  爸爸
Just like you taught me, Papa.
我爱你  儿子
Love you, beta.
再见  卡什  我也爱你  妈妈
Bye, Kash. Love you, too, Mama.
说起来...
In fact...
我在台上的时候会向你们飞吻的
I'll blow you a kiss when I'm on stage.
卡什...
Kashi...
把电视打开
put on the telly.
-你好呀  玛丽  -你好  布莱恩
- Hello, Mary! - Hi, Brian!
我们是过来祝你们好运的
We just came to wish you good luck.
你好呀  吾爱
Hello, my love.
你好
Hi.
玛丽  大卫
Mary, David...
这位是吉姆
this is Jim.
吉姆
Jim...
这是玛丽和大卫
Mary and David.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
-你好  -你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
之后见
I'll see you after.
你在这儿是什么也看不到的
I don't think you're gonna be able to see anything from here.
和他们一起去吧
Join them.
你们觉得大卫怎么样
What do we think of David?
挺好的小伙子
Nice chap.
我觉得他是基佬
I think he's gay.
我们将于大约一分钟后开始
We'll be on in about one minute.
一二  一二
One, two. One, two.
不要动
不要
快到我们了
That's almost us.
准备好了吗
We ready?
感觉不错吧
Feel good?
有人投诉我们声音过大
So we have had a bit of a complaint about the noise.
不要动
不要
是一位在比利时的女士
From a woman in Belgium.
不要动
不要
总而言之...
Anyway...
我们非常荣幸地请出下一支乐队
it gives us enormous pleasure to introduce the next combo...
他们就是...
who are...
皇后乐队
Queen!
女王殿下
Her Majesty...
皇后乐队
Queen!
没有
Nothing.
拯救生命
♪ 妈妈 ♪
♪ Mama ♪
♪ 我刚杀了人 ♪
♪ Just killed a man ♪
♪ 用枪指着他的头 ♪
♪ Put a gun against his head ♪
♪ 扣下扳机  他命归西 ♪
♪ Pulled my trigger, now he's dead ♪
♪ 妈妈 ♪
♪ Mama ♪
♪ 人生才刚开始 ♪
♪ Life had just begun ♪
♪ 但如今我却将其全抛弃 ♪
♪ But now I've gone and thrown it all away ♪
♪ 妈妈 ♪
♪ Mama ♪
♪ 并非有意惹你哭 ♪
♪ Didn't mean to make you cry ♪
♪ 如果明日此时我还未归 ♪
♪ If I'm not back again this time tomorrow ♪
♪ 继续  生活 ♪
♪ Carry on, carry on ♪
♪ 装作没什么大不了的 ♪
♪ As if nothing really matters ♪
♪ 太迟了 ♪
♪ Too late ♪
♪ 我大限将至 ♪
♪ My time has come ♪
♪ 忍战栗爬我背脊 ♪
♪ Sends shivers down my spine ♪
♪ 浑身病痛无喘息 ♪
♪ Body's aching all the time ♪
♪ 再见  所有人啊 ♪
♪ Goodbye, everybody ♪
♪ 我必须走 ♪
♪ I've got to go ♪
♪ 不得不离你们而去面对真相 ♪
♪ Gotta leave you all behind and face the truth ♪
♪ 妈妈 ♪
♪ Mama ♪
♪ 我不想死 ♪
♪ I don't want to die ♪
♪ 有时我宁愿从未降生于世 ♪
♪ I sometimes wish I'd never been born at all ♪
♪ 我独坐着  看着你的光 ♪
♪ I'd sit alone and watch your light ♪
♪ 少年的夜晚中我唯一的朋友 ♪
♪ My only friend through teenage nights ♪
♪ 我所需要知道的一切 ♪
♪ And everything I had to know ♪
♪ 都是从我的收音机上听来的 ♪
♪ I heard it on my radio ♪
♪ 你创造出了许多旧时明星 ♪
♪ You gave them all those old-time stars ♪
♪ 都在《火星人入侵地球》的大战里 ♪
♪ Through wars of worlds invaded by Mars ♪
♪ 你让我们笑  你让我们哭 ♪
♪ You made 'em laugh, you made 'em cry ♪
♪ 你让我们觉得自己可展翅高飞 ♪
♪ You made us feel like we could fly ♪
♪ 所以请别沦为某种背景噪音 ♪
♪ So don't become some background noise ♪
♪ 沦为男孩女孩的背景板 ♪
♪ A backdrop for the girls and boys ♪
♪ 他们不懂  也不在乎 ♪
♪ Who just don't know or just don't care ♪
♪ 但你缺席时他们却会抱怨 ♪
♪ And just complain when you're not there ♪
♪ 你有过高光时刻  也曾大权在握 ♪
♪ You had your time, you had the power ♪
♪ 但你最辉煌的时刻还尚未到来 ♪
♪ You've yet to have your finest hour ♪
♪ 收音机 ♪
♪ Radio ♪
大家一起
Everybody!
♪ 我们所闻皆是 ♪
♪ All we hear is - ♪
♪ 收音机嘎嘎 ♪
♪ Radio ga ga ♪
♪ 收音机咕咕 ♪
♪ Radio goo goo ♪
♪ 收音机嘎嘎 ♪
♪ Radio ga ga ♪
♪ 我们所闻皆是 ♪
♪ All we hear is ♪
♪ 收音机嘎嘎 ♪
♪ Radio ga ga ♪
♪ 收音机咕咕 ♪
♪ Radio goo goo ♪
♪ 收音机嘎嘎 ♪
♪ Radio ga ga ♪
♪ 我们所闻皆是 ♪
♪ All we hear is
♪ 收音机嘎嘎 ♪
♪ Radio ga ga ♪
♪ 收音机巴拉巴拉 ♪
♪ Radio blah blah ♪
♪ 收音机有什么新鲜事 ♪
♪ Radio, what's new? ♪
♪ 收音机 ♪
♪ Radio ♪
♪ 有人依旧爱着你 ♪
♪ Someone still loves you ♪
♪ 爱着 ♪
♪ Loves ♪
♪ 你 ♪
♪ You ♪
-好啦  -好啦
- All right! - All right!
《命运降临》
Hammer to Fall!
♪ 我们成功  亦或失意 ♪
♪ Here we stand or here we fall ♪
♪ 历史完全不在意 ♪
♪ History don't care at all ♪
♪ 铺好床  打开灯 ♪
♪ Make the bed, light the light ♪
♪ "仁慈"女士今晚给你闭门羹 ♪
♪ Lady Mercy won't be home tonight ♪
♪ 你一分一秒都不曾散漫 ♪
♪ You don't waste no time at all ♪
♪ 没听到钟声却响应了召唤 ♪
♪ Don't hear the bell but you answer the call ♪
♪ 我们一样都要接受审判 ♪
♪ It comes to you as to us all ♪
♪ 命运是时候降临 ♪
♪ And it's time for the hammer to fall ♪
♪ 每一夜  每一日 ♪
♪ Every night, every day ♪
♪ 你都有一小块自己正在消逝 ♪
♪ A little piece of you is falling away ♪
♪ 仰起脸用西方国家方式 ♪
♪ But lift your face the Western way ♪
♪ 站上起跑线  参与他们的游戏  ♪
♪ Toe your line and play their game ♪
♪ 命运是时候降临 ♪
♪ Then it's time for the hammer to fall ♪
♪ 富贵  贫穷  或出名 ♪
♪ Rich or poor or famous ♪
你好  "拯救生命"
Hello? Live Aid.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
您是想要捐款吗
Would you like to make a donation?
你好  "拯救生命"
Hello? Live Aid.
你好  这里是"拯救生命"演唱会
Hello? This is Live Aid.
♪ 哦不 ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ 锁上门 ♪
♪ Lock your door ♪
你好  "拯救生命"
Hello, Live Aid.
总金额
-我们刚刚到了一百万  -一百万英镑
- We just hit a million! - One million pounds!
-一百万英镑  -谢谢  太棒了
- One million pounds! - Thanks. Great.
♪ 我们生于蘑菇云的阴影中 ♪
♪ For you who grew up tall and proud ♪
♪ 成长得茁壮又自豪 ♪
♪ In the shadow of the mushroom cloud ♪
♪ 明知我们的声音无法被听见 ♪
♪ Convinced our voices can't be heard ♪
♪ 但只想呐喊得大声大声更大声 ♪
♪ Just wanna scream it louder And louder and louder ♪
♪ 我们到底在为什么而战 ♪
♪ What the hell we fighting for? ♪
♪ 如今命运是时候是时候降临 ♪
♪ And it's time for the hammer to hammer to fall ♪
♪ 很好  再来一次 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, one more time! ♪
♪ 等待着命运降临 ♪
♪ Waiting for the hammer to fall ♪
给我再来一次
Give it to me one more time!
♪ 我已付出代价 ♪
♪ I've paid my dues ♪
♪ 一次又一次 ♪
♪ Time after time ♪
♪ 我已接受刑罚 ♪
♪ I've done my sentence ♪
♪ 但却没有犯罪 ♪
♪ But committed no crime ♪
♪ 至于糟糕的错误 ♪
♪ And bad mistakes - ♪
♪ 我犯过几个 ♪
♪ I've made a few ♪
♪ 我接受了足够多的惩罚 ♪
♪ I've had my share of sand kicked in my face ♪
♪ 但我都挺过来了 ♪
♪ But I've come through ♪
♪ 我们是冠军  我的朋友 ♪
♪ We are the champions, my friends ♪
♪ 我们将会战斗直至终点 ♪
♪ And we'll keep on fighting till the end ♪
♪ 我们是冠军 ♪
♪ We are the champions ♪
♪ 没时间给败将 ♪
♪ No time for losers ♪
♪ 因为我们是冠军 ♪
♪ 'Cause we are the champions ♪
♪ 是世界之王 ♪
♪ Of the world ♪
♪ 我已鞠躬谢幕 ♪
♪ I've taken my bows ♪
♪ 如今帷幕落下 ♪
♪ And my curtain calls ♪
♪ 你们让我名利双收 ♪
♪ You brought me fame and fortune ♪
♪ 还有其他随之而来的一切好处 ♪
♪ And everything that goes with it ♪
♪ 我感谢你们 ♪
♪ I thank you all ♪
♪ 但这并非玫瑰花床 ♪
♪ But it's been no bed of roses ♪
♪ 也不是享乐游轮 ♪
♪ No pleasure cruise ♪
♪ 我将其视作是摆放在全人类面前的挑战 ♪
♪ I consider it a challenge before the whole human race ♪
♪ 而我绝不会输 ♪
♪ And I ain't gonna lose ♪
♪ 我们是冠军  我的朋友 ♪
♪ We are the champions, my friends ♪
♪ 我们将会战斗直至终点 ♪
♪ And we'll keep on fighting till the end ♪
♪ 我们是冠军 ♪
♪ We are the champions ♪
♪ 没时间给败将 ♪
♪ No time for losers ♪
♪ 因为我们是冠军 ♪
♪ 'Cause we are the champions ♪
♪ 我们是冠军  我的朋友 ♪
♪ We are the champions, my friends ♪
♪ 我们将会战斗直至终点 ♪
♪ And we'll keep on fighting till the end ♪
♪ 我们是冠军 ♪
♪ We are the champions ♪
♪ 没时间给败将 ♪
♪ No time for losers ♪
♪ 因为我们是冠军 ♪
♪ 'Cause we are the champions ♪
♪ 是世界之王 ♪
♪ Of the world ♪
再见  拜拜
So long and goodbye!
我爱你  弗雷迪
I love you Freddie!
我们爱你们
We love you!
Don't Stop Me Now
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ I'm gonna have myself ♪
♪ A real good time ♪
♪ I feel alive ♪
♪ And the world turning inside out Yeah! ♪
弗雷迪·默丘里于1991年11月24日
因艾滋引发的肺炎去世
享年45岁
♪ And floating around in ecstasy ♪
弗雷迪和吉姆的恋爱关系
一直持续到了弗雷迪逝世
♪ So don't stop me now ♪
弗雷迪和玛丽·奥斯汀
是一生的好友
♪ Don't stop me ♪
他因家族信仰
琐罗亚斯德教的传统
进行了火化
♪ 'Cause I'm having a good time having a good time ♪
♪ I'm a shooting star leaping through the sky ♪
《波西米亚狂想曲》
在两周之后重新发行
并再次登上榜首
♪ Like a tiger defying the laws of gravity ♪
当时距其初次发行已过去了16年
♪ I'm a racing car passing by like Lady Godiva ♪
1992年  皇后乐队和吉姆·比奇成立了"默丘里凤凰基金"
致力于在全球范围内防治艾滋病  以此纪念弗雷迪
♪ I'm gonna go go go ♪
♪ There's no stopping me ♪
♪ I'm burning through the sky Yeah! ♪
♪ Two hundred degrees ♪
♪ That's why they call me Mister Fahrenheit ♪
♪ I'm traveling at the speed of light ♪
♪ I wanna make a supersonic man out of you ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ I'm having such a good time ♪
♪ I'm having a ball ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ If you wanna have a good time ♪
♪ Just give me a call ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm havin' a good time ♪
♪ Yes I'm havin' a good time ♪
♪ I don't want to stop at all ♪
♪ I'm a rocket ship on my way to Mars ♪
♪ On a collision course ♪
♪ I am a satellite I'm out of control ♪
♪ I am a sex machine ready to reload ♪
♪ Like an atom bomb about to ♪
♪ Oh explode ♪
♪ I'm burning through the sky Yeah! ♪
♪ Two hundred degrees ♪
♪ That's why they call me Mister Fahrenheit ♪
♪ I'm traveling at the speed of light ♪
♪ I wanna make a supersonic woman of you ♪
♪ Don't stop me don't stop me don't stop me ♪
♪ Don't stop me don't stop me ♪
♪ I like it ♪
♪ Have a good time good time ♪
♪ Don't stop me don't stop me ♪
♪ I'm burning through the sky Yeah! ♪
♪ Two hundred degrees ♪
♪ That's why they call me Mister Fahrenheit ♪
♪ I'm traveling at the speed of light ♪
♪ I wanna make a supersonic man out of you ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ I'm having such a good time ♪
♪ I'm having a ball ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ If you wanna have a good time ♪
♪ Just give me a call ♪
♪ Don't stop me now ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm havin' a good time ♪
♪ Yes I'm havin' a good time ♪
♪ I don't want to stop at all ♪
The Show Must Go On
♪ Empty spaces ♪
♪ What are we living for ♪
♪ Abandoned places ♪
♪ I guess we know the score ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ Does anybody know what we are looking for ♪
♪ Another hero another mindless crime ♪
♪ Behind the curtain in the pantomime ♪
♪ Hold the line ♪
♪ Does anybody want to take it anymore ♪
♪ The show must go on ♪
♪ Inside my heart is breaking ♪
♪ My make-up may be flaking ♪
♪ But my smile still stays on ♪
♪ My soul is painted like the wings of butterflies ♪
♪ Fairy tales of yesterday will grow but never die ♪
♪ I can fly my friends ♪
♪ The show must go on ♪
♪ I'll face it with a grin ♪
♪ I'm never giving in ♪
♪ On with the show ♪
♪ I'll top the bill ♪
♪ I'll overkill ♪
♪ I have to find the will to carry on ♪
♪ On with the show ♪
♪ The show must go on ♪